I’m hungry, aren’t you?
I’m home.
Welcome home, Onee-chan.
Thank you for your hard work.
Dinner is almost ready, so please wait a bit.
Sure!
What’s for dinner tonight?
Tonight’s dinner is mushroom and potato stew over rice.
Thanks for the food!
It’s delicious!
I’m content as long as Asu is happy and healthy.
Her smile always makes me feel at ease.
But, sometimes I fail to understand Asu’s true feelings.
I regret it when I don’t notice that she’s sad.
Reminder about this year’s 4th
Reminder about this year’s 4th Parents' day
Parents' Day
When that happens, I always think,
“I have to hurry up and become a grown-up like mom!”
Mom went to heaven the year Asu was born.
Dad disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room,
dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes…
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when I’m on the verge of tears,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of Perfume,
Asu, and A Class Visit
This shirt is too childish.
This one and that one are, too.
Parents’ day, huh?
Ah, my mom’s here! Is yours here too, Kyou-chan?
My dad’s coming!
Rise.
Bow.
I guess dad’s still on his way.
All right! Who knows how to read this?
I do! I do! I do!
He’s still not here…
Let’s all read it together!
In the end, Taro said,
He’s just a little late. He’ll come for sure!
“We can all definitely look forward to both the happy times and the sad times,
as they are feelings that come from the very bottom of your heart…”
Dad, why didn’t you come?
You promised me!
Back then, I was jealous of everyone who just took it for granted that their parents would show up.
I missed Mom, who had gone to heaven, so much that I cried all night.
I don’t want Asu to have to go through that.
I’m here in Mom’s place, so I have to be there on parents’ day.
Even so, I don’t have anything appropriate to wear.
Onee-chan…
What are you doing?
Sorry, I didn’t mean to wake you.
What are you doing with all these clothes, Onee-chan?
For your parents’ day.
You haven’t mentioned them in the past, so I’ve never gone to one.
I want to be there this year.
Um, Onee-chan,
it’s fine if you don’t come.
Hmm?
It’s fine if you don’t come.
What?! You don’t want your big sister to go?!
Ah, no, that’s not it.
It’s just that you have school too, right?
Ah, that’s right.
Thank you, Onee-chan. It’s all right if you don’t come.
Please don’t worry about it.
Anyway, if you don’t get some sleep, you’ll be too tired to deliver newspapers tomorrow morning.
Right?
Y-Yeah.
Even though she says it’s because I have school too,
all her classmates’ parents will be there, right?
Maybe she’s embarrassed that I’m just a middle-schooler.
If I had some clothes that would make me look more grown-up, I’d be fine.
Dry
Cleaning
Th-This is…!
Asu!
Onee-chan, welcome home.
I found a w-wallet in front of our a-apartment!
A wallet?
What should we do?
Wh-Wh-What should we do?
Calm down, Onee-chan.
Does it have anything with a name or an address in it?
There’s a ton of money in here!
Yeah.
With this much money,
we could pay the month’s rent, buy groceries, and get any cake that we want!
We could buy you some new clothes!
That’s right! With this much money,
I’d be able to buy something grown-up to wear to parents’ day.
No, no!
The person who lost this wallet is probably in trouble.
Let’s take it to the police.
You need to go deliver the newspaper, right?
I can take it.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Are you really going to be okay?
I’ll be fine.
You worry too much, Onee-chan.
You’re carrying around a fortune, so make sure you don’t go off with anyone suspicious.
Okay!
Hey, you!
You’re the little sister from next door, right?
Ah, the lady from next door!
Hel—
I was the one who dropped that wallet. Give it back to me, will you?
Suspicious…
Even though it’s someone we know, she still seems suspicious, Onee-san.
Inside the wallet there’s an ID Card, right? The name is Saegusa Ranko.
You’re right!
I’m glad I was able to return it to you!
Little miss, from up close you’re awfully cute.
Let me thank you for this. Come on.
Mental math practice with
gram-to-price ratios improves grades.
Which is the
better bargain?
Gather together a lot of little
soap shavings to wash a big back.
A chocolate parfait, along with strawberry shortcake, and pudding à la mode!
Now, don’t be shy; eat up.
O-Okay!
Make sure you don’t go off with anyone suspicious.
What’s wrong? You don’t like sweets?
Onee-chan told me not to accept things from suspic—f-from people who I don’t know very well.
I guess these sunglasses make me look pretty shady, huh?
Well then…
She looks like a nice person.
Thanks for the food!
Onee-chan would probably like to eat some of this cake, too.
Hey,
you still won’t eat it?
Um, would it be okay to take this home instead?
I’d like to split it with my big sister.
The cake?
Yes.
You can eat all that by yourself.
We can keep this as our little secret from your big sister.
All this, by myself?
We’d be able to buy Asu’s favorite cake, too!
I think my big sister would do the same thing if she were in my shoes.
Excuse me! Hey! Excuse me!
Thank you so much!
You’re welcome.
There’s something I’ve wanted to ask you since we last met.
Yes?
You two… it’s just you and your sister living alone next door?
Yes.
What about your mother and father?
Dad is… living somewhere else.
Mom is… gone.
Sorry for asking such a strange question.
I was simply curious.
It’s okay.
As long as Onee-chan is here with me, I’m fine.
I see.
Yes.
But I do sometimes wonder why mom’s not here any more.
Every once in a while.
Let’s dig in!
Delicious!
So delicious!
The lady next door is really a good person.
I’ll have to go thank her after we finish this!
Yes! I’ll come too!
You already thanked her, so it’s okay.
There’s still some tidying up to do after dinner, anyway.
Well, okay.
Leave it to me!
Thank you for the cake.
Asu also thought it was delicious.
Oh my, you’re awfully cute too, now that I get a good look.
From now on, let’s be friends, okay?
Ah, sure.
Well, see you later.
Compared to the person who yelled at us for being too loud,
she seems like a completely different person.
It would be great if I could become a grown-up like her.
I’d be able to attend parents’ day without embarrassing Asu.
Um…
Yes?
This might be a rude thing to ask, but…
What is it?
If you have any suits, could you please lend me one?
A suit?
I do have a few, but what do you need one for?
I want to go to parents’ day for my sister!
I want to fill in for mom,
but I need something more formal to wear!
Please!
But I do sometimes wonder why mom’s not here any more.
If that’s how it is, I’ll lend you as many suits as you want!
Th-Thank you so much!
Here, come on in.
Y-Yes! With pleasure!
For parents’ day at a primary school, you shouldn’t wear anything too revealing.
Mountains of garbage?
It’s a little messy, but don’t mind it.
Maybe a light pink, or perhaps blue?
I wonder what Saegusa-san does…
Alright!
This one should do it.
What do you think?
It’s amazing!
It looks great on you! You look very mature.
Really?
Yes, really. Have some confidence!
Finally, put on a little bit of perfume, and…
Perfect.
Thank you very much.
I’ll make sure to get them cleaned.
Don’t you worry about that.
I’ll let you hold on to them until tomorrow.
How about it?
Wh-What happened, Onee-chan?
I borrowed this from the lady next door!
Y-You put on perfume, too?
Yup.
This way I can take over for Mom, right?
Onee-chan.
Yes?
Don’t force yourself to come to parents’ day.
What?
Asu…
I’m not forcing myself…
Ah! Oh no, the bath will close soon.
Onee-chan, let’s go.
Ah, okay.
Bath House Hawaii
Don’t force yourself to come to parents’ day.
I guess I’m no good after all.
Too bad… back to same old me.
Thank goodness.
It’s Onee-chan’s usual smell.
Onee-chan, stop trying to take someone else’s place.
You’re my older sister.
Stay that way.
Just keep being your normal self.
Ok. I will.
In order to protect Asu from that same lonely and painful memory,
I wanted to dress up and take Mother’s place on parents’ day.
But now I realize that the reason I wanted to act and dress like an adult
was mostly because I was afraid of being embarrassed myself.
Looking at Asu’s face,
it seems like she’s really trying hard to fight back her loneliness.
Asu-chan, who are you looking for?
Oh, nobody in particular.
There’s no way she’ll come.
Class is starting!
Today is parents’ day, and all your parents are here. Everyone, just try to act the same as usual.
The writing here is the kanji for autumn (秋) with “Grade 3, class 1” (三年一組) written on the side, above the name of the student.
Oh my, who’s that? A middle school student?
If Asu wants me to stay just the way I am,
then there’s no reason for me to be embarrassed.
Well then, Yamada-san, can you read for us from page 94?
Y-Yes!
In the end, Taro said,
“We can all definitely look forward to both the happy times and the sad times,
I’m here to observe you.
as these are feelings that come from the very bottom of your heart…”
I always regret it when I don’t recognize Asu’s true feelings.
But I’m watching her with my own eyes,
and striving to protect her.
If that makes Asu feel safe and happy,
I’m definitely keeping my promise to you,
right, Mom?
Hey, Onee-chan, what did you do about school?
I just left early.
Onee-chan.
Yeah?
Thank you.
The truth is…
The truth is, I really did want you to come!
I knew that all along!
Geez.
All right! Next time you have a class visit, I’m going to be there.
Hey now, I’m not so sure about that.
Huh? Why not?
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo “fuwari” naderu
おてこを“ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agarou
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
Binbou   Shimai Monogatari
Asu! What should we do?
The landlord told us we need to move out of the apartment immediately!
Onee-chan, where will we go?
Poor Sisters’ Story:
“A day of the Apartment, Sakura, and Moving”.
Please watch it!