Dear Onee-sama,
today, I failed to get the spinach that was on sale.
Am I really qualified to be your younger sister?
You must hate your little sister who fails repeatedly, after all.
No matter how hard I try, it’s never enough to make you notice.
Yamada Kyou,
Yamada Asu, huh…
Mom went to heaven the year Asu was born.
Dad disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room,
dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes…
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when I’m on the verge of tears,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of Loneliness,
Ginko, and Onee-sama
What!? It’s already this late?!
Onee-chan, wake up!
Wake up! We’re going to be late!
Just three more minutes…
This room is really dark, even in the morning.
All because that high-rise got built next door.
The weather’s great today.
It looks like picking the penthouse was the right choice after all, Onee-sama.
You’d better hurry, Ginko. You’re going to be late.
Yes, Onee-sama.
I requested for father to build the apartments here so you would be closer to your school.
O-Okay.
You will not be allowed to be late.
Y-Yes, Onee-sama.
Even better, it’ll be much easier to find great sales from here!
Right.
All we need are some pencils…
Nothing makes me happier than free things.
Weren’t they already cheap?
“Economizing”. Oh, it sounds so marvelous.
I can’t handle much more of this.
Well then, I’ll be going ahead by car.
I’ll be home late.
H-H-Have a safe trip.
Onee-sama is busy today, too.
Onee-chan, hurry up!
Okay!
If you don’t hurry, we’re going to be late!
Ah, it’s Ginko-chan!
Good morning!
Good morning.
So you guys moved into the new apartment complex!
Amazing, isn’t it?
Well, your old house was amazing too, of course.
My father is the owner of these apartments.
Because of that, we can live on whatever floor we want, but the penthouse is definitely the best one.
Maybe I’ll invite you over someday.
Onee-chan, your scarf is a little crooked.
Thanks, Asu.
Hey! Listen to me!
Ah, sorry.
Um…
What were you talking about?
Onee-chan, we really need to…
Ah, that’s right.
We’re going to be late, so let’s chat later.
See you later!
Ah, me too!
What the heck is it with those two?
Ah, I barely made it in time.
Could it be that the two of
them are always like that?
Rise.
Bow.
That’s just not the way things are between my sister and me.
Good morning.
Be seated.
Holding hands like that… how embarrassing.
Class representative.
Class representative!
Ah, yes?
What’s wrong? Come by the office later to pick up the printouts.
Okay, I got it.
Excuse me.
You’re also a class representative?
Yeah.
Everyone pushed the job on you, right?
I had to run for it.
When I become a fifth grader, I’m going to run for the student council, too.
Ah, there you are!
I’ll definitely be elected president!
Asu-chan, can you please help me with the next part on this?
Oh, sure.
Hey! Listen to me!
Ah, sorry, Ginko-chan.
Please wait just a moment.
It’s this part here.
This part here helps to explain this other part here, which leads to—
Oh, I see! I get it now!
Asu-chan, you’re amazing!
Let me help you carry that.
What up with her?
She’s just letting herself get used.
Right?
You don’t seem busy.
Help pass these out.
Sorry, but we’re a little busy right now.
Let’s go.
Okay.
Echigoya-san is really annoying, don’t you think?
Yeah.
Ginko-chan, sorry about what happened earlier.
Don’t follow me!
Didn’t I tell you to not follow me?!
We walk home the same way, though…
Asu-chan, are you heading home?
Good afternoon.
You know, we made a little bit too much for today, so please take this home with you.
Wow, it looks delicious!
Thank you very much!
You’re welcome.
Hey, Asu-chan!
These are today’s leftovers. Take them with you!
Ah, okay. Thank you.
Asu-chan! I have some leftovers, too.
Ah. Okay!
Asu-chan, wait! You’d better take this too!
Okay. Thank you very much.
The way you and your sister get by on your own is really something.r, that’s amazing.}
It’s rare to see that these days.
Here, this is from our store.
Here. Extras, extras, take ’em.
Oh, you’ve grown a bit taller, haven’t you?
What do you mean it’s “really something”?
I’m also—I’m also trying my best with my older sister.
Why is it? Why is it—?!
I won’t lose to you!
I won’t lose to you two!
Why, why, why?!
Just because she’s nicer, has more
friends, and gets along with everyone!
Onee-sama and I are just so much, much, much—!
Ginko.
Yes?
I had that long-range telescope that you asked for yesterday carried up from the ground floor.
Thank you very much, Onee-sama.
You asked for it so suddenly, I was wondering how on earth you were planning to use it.
You plan on doing some pretty risky things with it, right?
Ginko.
You’re going to use this to…
Scout out all the supermarkets in the city for super-extraordinary sales, am I right?
That’s wonderful, Ginko.
Right, Onee-sama.
If it’s for the great cause of economization, I’ll even lend you a helicopter if you want.
Onee-sama, I don’t think we need to go that far…
Whatever you’re doing, it’s a great idea.
You should search every single supermarket for deals, even if it takes you the whole day.y, you have to find out every supermarket that has special sales.}
Sound good?
S-Sure.
I’m sorry, Onee-sama.
That’s not why I asked for the telescope.
I have to go now, so I’ll leave the rest to you.
What? You’re busy today too?
But we have the day off.
Yes. I won’t be back until late tonight.
Is that so?
Have a good day.
Mistress, I’ve finished adjusting the settings.
I’ll take care of the rest.
Begone.
Understood.
I’m aware that I really shouldn’t be doing this,
but I have to do it so I can find out just what it is that’s so different about them.
We should be perfect.
Even so, even so…
Yamada Asu!
I will definitely not lose to you!
On a cold night, if you eat
shichimi, it will help keep you warm.
7 Delicious Spices
To us, the flea market is like
an enormous shopping mall.
Thanks for the food!
It’s delicious!
The eggs and spinach is delicious!
Two days ago, I found the spinach on sale for 40 yen per bag.
I cooked it with some eggs I found yesterday for 58 yen!
Ah! The spinach from the sale that I missed!
Why does she open her
mouth so wide while eating?
Onee-sama would never do such an improper thing.
She even has grains of rice stuck to her face.
Why do they act so uncivilized?
Onee-chan, your face has some rice stuck to it, you know.
Oh my, you’re right.
Ah, Onee-chan, the miso soup also came out really well today.
I’ve never laughed during a meal before.
Talking with a full mouth is simply reprehensible behavior!
What’s wrong, Asu?
Oh, it’s nothing.
Today’s a holiday, so she’s sleeping on the floor in the middle of the day?
I’ve never seen Onee-sama being that lazy.
Even until she goes to bed, she’s always energetic and—
Ginko, good night.
Onee-sama, perhaps you’re a little too energetic.
Why does she always seem so happy to take care of her troublesome older sister?
It’s rough, isn’t it, Yamada Asu.
My sister is never troublesome or dependent on me.
Ah, Kyou-chan, Asu-chan, good afternoon.
Good afternoon!
What’s this, the two of you are out for a walk?
Yeah.
You two sure seem to get along well.
You’re nothing like my kids.
They’re always fighting with each other.
They could learn a thing or two from you guys.
No way, you’re flattering us, ma’am.
Ta-da!
Asu, go ahead and pick whichever one you like.
I’ll take this one—the dried tuna!
I’ll go with the picked plum, then.
Let’s eat!
Asu, this pickled plum rice ball is really good!
All they ever think about is food, huh?
All rice balls taste the same no matter who makes them.
There’s absolutely no reason for me to be jealous of them.
Asu-chan, you’re early today, aren’t you?
Good afternoon!
Thank you for yesterday.
We have the day off today, so I came together with my sister!
Mister, do you have anything that’s especially cheap today?r, are there any cheap fish?}
Those two have been together since they woke up.
Mistress Ginko, don’t you think that spying on people is a little…
I’m through with it.
Watching any more would be a waste of time.
What’s wrong, Asu?
For some reason I’ve been on edge today.
It kind of feels like someone is watching us.
That’s kinda odd, Asu.
Hey, isn’t it time for you to deliver the newspaper?
Ah, this is bad! Today’s the evening edition, isn’t it?
Sorry, can you take these home?
They’re a little heavy. See ya!
Take care!
I’m home!
Onee-chan, welcome home.
Dinner is ready.
Ah, thank you.
Mistress Ginko, we’ve completed the dinner preparations.
Just leave it there.
Very well.
Wait.
Yes, is there something you need?
Father hasn’t come home yet?
Your father has not yet returned from his trip to Los Angeles.
And your mother—
That’s enough.
That’s enough. You’re dismissed.
Thanks for the food!
Asu! This Salmon Meunière is the best!
The man from the fish market was nice enough to sell us this salmon at a really low price,
and the side dishes are from the owner of the vegetable stand.
“Meunier” certainly has a rich sound to it.
Even though I only sprinkled a few croûtons on top.
I’m all right.
I’m fine with being alone.
I was fine, but…
But still, why?
Why am I still drawn to the light from that window?
Come over to my house.
Wha—?
I told you before that I’d invite you over!
But it’s already so late, and shouldn’t you ask your family for permission firs—
There’s nobody there to ask!
Wow! It’s so beautiful!
Yeah, isn’t it amazing?
The building over there, the tallest one, is ours too.
Along with that one, and that one.
In this area we own a bunch—
No, no, Onee-chan! We’re in someone else’s house!
You can’t fall asleep here!
I’m sorry, it’s just that she’s usually asleep by this time.
Onee-cha—!
Ah, she really fell asleep.
She’s not a very reliable older sister, is she?
That’s why you’re always working so hard.
It’s tough, isn’t it.
It’s not tough at all.
It’s okay. Don’t lie.
If it’s for Onee-chan, I’ll do my very best.
Every day, she attends school and works as well.
She’s really the one who has it rough.
Onee-sama…
Because I can’t get a real job yet,
for Onee-chan’s sake,
I want to make our home the one place in the world where she doesn’t have to work hard.
A place where she doesn’t have to work hard…
Yes.
Asu, this fried sweet potato is also really delicious.
Well then, we’ll head home now.
Okay.
Onee-chan, it’s time to go.
Yes… It’s delicious.
Geez…
What can I do for my sister?
Excuse me…
Excuse us!
Onee-sama always does her best to meet the expectations of those around her,
and I’ve never heard her once complain about how tough it is.
Onee-sama is the one who is always alone.
No, I was the one who abandoned her.
Mistress Kinko, will it be satisfactory to leave Mistress Ginko’s new clothes here?
Sure. Just leave them on the table.
But…
It’s fine. I’ll take care of them.
Understood.
Well then, I’ll retire for today.
Thank you.
Onee-sa—
Onee-sama.
You’re not asleep yet?
No.
You should hurry to bed, Ginko. You have school tomorrow.
What about you, Onee-sama?
There are still some things that I have to take care of.
My laundry—you’re the one who always folds it for me, aren’t you?
Onee-sama!
Onee-sama, please don’t push yourself too hard!
Ginko.
I understand.
Thank you, Ginko.
Dear Onee-sama,
today I noticed something for the first time.
I was the one who was wrong.
I was always thinking only about myself.
I didn’t even notice how much you have been taking care of me all this time.
I finally understand.
The most precious feelings are those that two people share for each other.
That’s why I love you, Onee-sama.
I should be able to create it.
A place where she doesn’t have to work hard.
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo “fuwari” naderu
おてこを“ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agarou
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
Binbou   Shimai Monogatari
Please accept this chocolate.
Onee-chan has someone who she likes.
Poor Sisters’ Story:
“A day of Jealousy, Chocolates, and Valentines”.
Please watch it!