For whom shall I sing?
I dislike music.
My heart always manages to find
some sadness in the flowing notes.
For whose sake does music exist?
It’s that voice again!
Asu!
Is it really some woman’s ghost?
D-Don’t worry, Onee-chan.
I’m here for you.
Thank you, Asu.
You’re really brave, Asu!
No, I’m not really…
Mom went to heaven the year Asu was born.
Dad disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room,
dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes…
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when I’m on the verge of tears,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of Guitars, Dreams,
and a Music Teacher
Good morning, Asu-chan.
Good morning.
Want to compare answers for last night’s homework?
Me too, me too.
Okay, sure.
Good morning.
Good morning, sir!
That’s it! Thanks a bunch, Asu-chan!
There’s nothing you can’t do!
Indeed, indeed.
That’s not true.
You don’t have any weak points, do you?
Yeah, she doesn’t seem to have any, does she?
You’re wrong.
It must be nice.
I bet it is. I’m pretty bad at arithmetic, you know.
I’m just human like everyone else.
Music Room
I’m completely tone-deaf.
Okay. Let’s start the music test!
Aida-san.
Yes, Ma’am.
Well, then.
Spring’s small brook babbles along,
winding past the violets and lotus flowers on its banks.
What’ll I do?
Ah, I’m terribly nervous. This won’t do!
Asu-chan, you’re the last one on the list, so
you’ll probably be going next week, right?
With its kind appearance and beautiful colors,
Y-yeah.
Are you okay? You’re looking a little pale.
it murmurs to them, “Blossom! Bloom!”
I’m fine. It’s nothing.
I’m looking forward to hearing you sing!
I bet you’re really talented!
That’s not true! I’m completely tone-deaf!
Okay! Next person.
The people who say that are always the talented ones, right?
You’re right. It seems like Asu-chan is just that type of person, too.
Spring’s small brook babbles along,
N-No, that’s not true at all. I really am tone-deaf.
We can’t wait!
winding past the violets and lotus flowers on its banks.
They’ll be terribly disappointed… What’ll I do?
I have a full week from today, so I’ll practice every day.
Spring’s small brook…
My voice sounds terrible.
…winding past the violets and lotus flowers on its banks.
What a beautiful voice…
With its kind appearance and beautiful colors,
Is there someone singing outside?
it murmurs to them, “Blossom! Bloom!”
She’s beautiful…
…or wait, maybe she’s a he?
Good afternoon. You’re my neighbor, right?
Y-Yes, I am.
It’s a pleasure to meet you.
It’s nice to meet you, too.
Um… you’re very good at singing, aren’t you?
Well, my dream is to become a singer.
You’re a singer? That’s amazing!
Not at all.
I haven’t debuted yet. I’m currently just auditioning over and over again.
B-But you sing so wonderfully!
I’m completely tone-deaf.
Hey, listen—
Masao!
It seems that you have a guest.
Masao! Are you in there?
Yeah.
I’ll be right back. Wait for me, okay?
“Masao-san”. So he is a guy.
I’m coming right now.
It’s me! Me!
Yes?
I brought you something.
Thanks.
Eat properly, okay?
Okay.
See you!
Yes?
Masao-san, I made a boxed lunch for you.
Thanks.
I’m really looking forward to your next live show!
I’ll come again later.
Yes?
Masao-san, um, I hope this isn’t a bother, but…
Oh, not at all. Thank you.
Farewell!
Sorry for the wait.
That’s really something.
Are they your friends?
Actually, I don’t really know them very well.
But they really appreciate my songs.
I also want to hear them.
That’s right, one of them said she was looking forward to hearing you play.
Where do you perform?
Last time it was at a live music club,
but at the moment I’m taking a break.
I completely ran out of money, so I can’t afford any more studio time;
I can hardly afford the rent here.
I’ve even thought about returning to the countryside,
but with the support of my fans, I can still eat regularly.
So I figured, what the heck.
Usually when I feel like singing, it’s already nighttime.
That ghostly voice was him all along.
Oh yeah, I’m Ichinokura Masao. And you?
I’m Yamada Asu.
It’s good, you know.
Your song, that is.
Well, I’ll see you later.
Thanks for the food!
It’s good, you know. Your song, that is.
If I practice a lot, I wonder if I’ll ever be able to sing like him.
Asu!
Asu! Asu! It’s that voice again!
It’s all right, Onee-chan. Listen carefully.
Glittering, sparkling,
basking in the rays of sunlight.
The voice is singing?
Yes.
In that way.
That’s a really pretty voice.
A rustling heart is
I wish I had noticed this sooner.
It’s a really, really beautiful song.
a memory of summer.
In that way.
Ah, good evening. Was I disturbing you?
Not at all, it was a wonderful song.
Good evening. I’m Asu’s older sister, Yamada Kyou.
Nice to meet you.
S-Same here.
It seems like it’s gotten colder, doesn’t it?
Looks like that’s all I’ve got for today.
Well then, goodnight.
Goodnight.
Goal:
A Doctorate
of Wild Grasses
Memorize all of the
edible items in the
plant encyclopedia.
On a walk, the keen-eyed
can quickly identify
edible grasses.
I need get home and practice singing!
I wonder if I’ll be able to sing like Ichinokura-san one day.
I suppose that’s not possible.
Oh, it’s Ichinokura-san.
Good afternoon!
Oh, good afternoon, Asu.
Are you on your way home?
Yes, I’m going to go practice sing—
Um, if it’s okay with you…
Please teach me… Please teach me how to sing. Please!
We have to take a singing test at school…
It’s probably impossible, so it’s okay if you decline.
But…
Sure.
You really will? Thank you very much!
Well then, let’s get started.
Did you bring anything that can play music?
Um…
A melodica, eh?
Well, I guess it’s good enough.
Try making the same sounds as it.
Okay.
Do!
Re!
Mi!
Huh? It won’t make the Fa and La sounds.
It’s a hand-me-down from my sister, and it’s slightly damaged.
Can’t you just ask your mom to buy you a new one?
We… don’t have a mom… or a dad.
It’s just the two of you living in that apartment?
Yes.
I’m sorry. I had no idea.
It’s all right! I still have my sister.
Um, if there’s ever anything I can help with, please ask.
But you’re already teaching me how to sing,
s-so…
I’d like to listen to your singing.
Okay, leave it to me. I’ll sing for you any time.
To be able to sing in tune and project properly,
Muscle training menu
Sit-ups: 30
Push-ups: 20
Muscle training menu
Sit-ups: 30
Push-ups: 20
Muscle training menu
Sit-ups: 30
Push-ups: 20
Muscle training menu
Sit-ups: 30
Push-ups: 20
strong muscles are absolutely essential!
Okay!
Test!
One!
Two!
From then on, with Ichinokura-san’s guidance and help,
Three!
And again, using your diaphragm! Hoo!
I continued to practice my singing.
Onee-chan practiced too.
Twenty-five!
Keep going, Asu!
Twenty-six!
Spring’s small brook babbles along,
Test!
winding past the violets and lotus flowers on its banks.
With its kind appearance and beautiful colors,
Music Room
it murmurs to them, “Blossom! Bloom!”
That’s it. You did very well.
Okay!
Asu-chan, that was really great!
How can you sing so well?
I guess I just had a really good teacher.
You did it, Asu!
Thanks, Onee-chan.
We should tell Ichinokura-san, too.
Ah, that’s right. Let’s go.
Ichinokura-san! I did really well on my test!
Maybe he’s not home?
I’m sure he’ll be back soon.
Test!
It looks like he still isn’t back.
A whole week has gone by,
and Ichinokura-san hasn’t come back yet.
Test!
I wonder what happened to Ichinokura-san.
Masao! Are you in there, Masao?
Masao?
Excuse me…
What? Who are you?
Um…
We’re his next-door neighbors.
Ichinokura-san hasn’t been
home for the whole week.
Have you heard anything from him?
As if!
We told him we’d keep helping him until his next audition, but it seems he deserted us.
Even though he said he would try his best this time!
Then, that means, when he told me he had sold his favorite guitar…
You know he’d never sell it! Masao-san
treasures that guitar more than his own life.
So that’s what happened.
Even though he was having his own
problems, he still taught me how to sing.
And his music was so wonderful!
And yet…
I’d like to listen to your singing.
Okay, leave it to me. I’ll sing for you any time.
Even though he promised me!
He promised that he’d sing for me again!
Flowing easily along,
His song… I can hear it.
His song…
the wind whispers by.
You’re right!
In that way.
Where is it?
That way!
In the radiant fields of green,
Where?
Masao-san!
let’s invite—
H-Hey.
Geez, Masao!
Where did you go?
Everyone was worried about you!
Masao-san.
Thank goodness.
I was spending nights at my part time job.
It seems I caused you some undue worry.
You idiot!
I’m so glad.
Next time, make sure to tell us beforehand!
I’m sorry.
Everyone loves Ichinokura-san, don’t they?
Yeah.
After being turned down at all my auditions,
I started thinking that becoming a
musician might be impossible for me.
I decided to give up singing for good.
But…
But, I do want to keep on singing.
That’s why I got a part time job, so I could afford to reclaim my guitar.
His guitar…
Because I made a promise.
A promise that I would sing for you again.
Flowing easily along,
I sing.
That’s what I can do. The only thing I can do.
the wind whispers by.
In that way.
Music is mysterious.
With the ebb and flow of each note,
In the radiant fields of green,
I can feel my spirits rising.
let’s invite the spring.
That’s why I will keep on singing.
In that way.
Glittering, sparkling,
basking in the rays of sunlight.
That’s why I want to stay here forever.
In that way.
A rustling heart is
I’ll try my best with Onee-chan.
So we will always be able to hear the music.
a memory of summer.
In that way.
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo “fuwari” naderu
おてこを“ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agarou
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
Binbou   Shimai Monogatari
Asu won a cellphone in a raffle.
Use it carefully!
Onee-chan, why aren’t you picking up your phone?
Poor Sisters’ Story:
“A Day of Emotions, Uneasiness, and Cell Phones”.
Please watch it!