I truly love Onee-chan.
She always tries her best at school and at work.
So to encourage her,
BIG 3-DAY SALE!!
Pork Tenderloin
Vegetables
Green Peppers
White Radish
tonight’s dinner will be cooked white radish, white radish miso soup, and white radish salad.
It’ll be fine.
To balance the meal,
I’ll add in yesterday’s cabbage along with some three-day-old potato leftovers.
But today’s main ingredient will definitely be white radishes.
That is…
I’m home.
Welcome home, Onee-chan!
Look, look!
White Radish
10 yen
How about it?
White radishes for for ten yen?
Let’s go! Right now!
Asu, let’s hurry!
Mom went to heaven the year Asu was born.
Dad disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room,
dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes…
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when I’m on the verge of tears,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of Carrots, Lies,
and the Echigoya Sisters
Super Cheap
It’s an amazing offer! White radishes are 10 yen each! Only 10 yen!
Grab one while supplies last!
Onee-chan, leave this to me!
Go ahead, Asu!
Ah, there’s only one left!
Ah, the last white radish…
Let’s go.
Okay.
The white radishes are all sold out!
We were just a bit too late.
Ah! Look, look, Onee-chan!
Tomorrow’s special is meat!
Meat?!
You’re right! It really is meat!
Pork Cutlets
100 grams of pork cutlets for only 88 yen!
How long has it been?
Tomorrow, let’s try harder!
Yes!
Meat! Tomorrow we’re having meat!
Asu-chan, you’re going home already?
Yes!
Today, pork cutlets are on sale for 88 yen.
See you!
It’s the girl from yesterday.
It seems she’s from the class next door.
She’s not going to the same supermarket again, is she?
I have to hurry.
Super Cheap
Calm down, there’s still a lot left!
Yes, here you go!
Pork cutlets for 88 yen!
Ah! There’s only one left!
Let go! I got here first.
No way…
This is mine!
Meat! Meat! We’re having yummy meat for dinner!
Meat!
No!
Please…
If I don’t buy this, my sister will yell at me.
Your sister… you mean that person from yesterday?
Don’t cry.
The meat’s mine.
Oh, please excuse me.
Thank goodness there was still one left.
The pork cutlets are sold out!
It’s all sold out!
Why wouldn’t you let me have it?
Is she faking it again?
Just because you wouldn’t let go…
No, she’s really crying.
What should I do? If I don’t bring that meat home, my sister will yell at me.
No, she’ll probably kick me out.
I might not have a home to go back to anymore.
If you tell her what happened, she’ll understand.
You’re only saying that because you don’t know my sister!
She’s a strict perfectionist,
so there’s no way she’ll understand!
Is she really that strict?
She’s completely different from my sister.
That’s right.
I know!
It’s your fault I can’t go home, so let me live at your house!
What?
Um, well…
I’m back.
Welcome home, Asu!
Aren’t you the girl from yesterday?
You see, Onee-chan, um…
I didn’t get any of the pork cutlets.
Ah, you don’t have to worry about that.
Here, see?
Onee-chan, how did you get this meat?
I told myself that I’d definitely make it to today’s big sale.
So, right after school, I rushed to the store.
To prevent yesterday’s events from happening again, I was twice as cautious.
Wow, you’re amazing, Onee-chan! As expected!
Thanks!
Onee-chan.
I have a request.
What’s wrong?
I want you to give this meat to her.
Her sister is very strict.
Without any of the meat from the sale, she can’t go home.
So, Onee-chan, give her the pork cutlets that you bought.
Please.
What are you talking about!? Forget about it!
Besides, there’s no way you’d just give that away to a stranger.
Here, take it.
How can you just give it away so easily?
Isn’t this your dinner?
Well, that’s because Asu asked me to.
Asu seriously wants me to give this to you.
I’m sure she has an important reason for asking.
After all, she wouldn’t ask without a reason.
And you! How can you so easily give away something that your sister worked so hard to buy?
Weren’t you worried your sister would yell at you?
Well, Onee-chan only gets angry when I do something that troubles others.
Even without the meat, we can still eat dinner together.
Even though meat is delicious, as long as I can eat dinner with Asu, anything will taste delicious.
Right?
It’s completely different in my family.
They don’t trust me at all, because I’m always making mistakes.
I think you need this pork more than we do.
Go make your sister proud of you, okay?
It’s getting late, let us take you home.
Th-Thank you.
And that is how our summer ended.
To this girl, the 100 grams of pork cutlets on sale for 88 yen
were probably important in building a bond of trust between her and her sister.
But why it had to be on sale was something Onee-chan and I didn’t understand.
Because, when she led us to her house…
My name is Echigoya Ginko.
This is my house.
Her house was fit for a king.
Keeping an eye out for
even a small discount,
Asu moves at full speed
One for 10 yen
Even the raindrops leaking
from the roof can sound
like a soothing orchestra
They have a lot of money, right?
Yeah. This is unbelievable.
Why does she have to buy food that’s on sale?
John!
I wonder why…
It’s dinner time.
It’s an alligator.
The pork was food for the alligator…
Ginko.
Onee-sama!
I am Echigoya Kinko, the older sister.
I’m Yamada Kyou.
I’m Asu.
Looks like they get along well.
Yes.
Onee-sama, I managed to buy the big sale item—
You didn’t buy it, right?
I was worried about you, so I followed you.
Why must you lie about it?
If you didn’t buy it, why didn’t you just honestly say so?
I’m sorry.
Ah, um…
I apologize for the trouble my sister gave you. Good day.
Ah, yes.
Will she be okay?
I’m sure she’ll be fine…
Tomorrow, at the supermarket in the next town…
1 day sale
3 carrots
for 50 yen
Carrots are on sale—three for 50 yen.
I wonder why the Echigoya sisters go bargain hunting.
It seems pointless since they’re rich.
I wonder why.
Ah!
Look, look, Onee-chan!
What? Did you find something?
Tomorrow at the supermarket in the next town, there’s a carrot sale—three for 50 yen.
That’s cheap!
I know!
Tomorrow, let’s have sautéed carrots over rice.
Okay, Onee-chan?
That’s right, sautéed carrots go pretty well with rice.
And we’ll get three for only 50 yen.
Asu-chan, you’ve been going home early lately.
Yeah!
See you later!
Three carrots for 50 yen!
What?
Ah! Three carrots for 50 yen!
With the rain, it’ll be a lot harder to get to that supermarket.
Ginko-chan…
I’m going too.
Ginko-chan!
I won’t lose!
Today, I have to buy them!
I will not fail!
Ginko-chan… just why are you trying so hard?
Just a little further…
Yes!
Man, I got here late.
Ah, as expected, they’re already sold out.
It’s difficult, isn’t it?
It really is difficult to save money, isn’t it?
R-Really?
for 50 yen
1 day sale
3 carrots
Yes, very.
for 50 yen
1 day sale
3 carrots
for 50 yen
1 day sale
3 carrots
for 50 yen
1 day sale
3 carrots
1-day sale
for 50 yen
It’s even harder than working for the student council.
It’s over. There’s no way I can go back home.
That’s not true! You just have to give your sister an honest explanation and she’ll understand.
I told you! My sister is a perfectionist!
Making the same mistake twice is unacceptable!
That and…
And…?
I’m sorry, but I must be going now.
Huh? You’re not going to go talk to her?
No, It wouldn’t do her any good.
All I do is make mistakes and disappoint my sister.
If I talk to her now, she’ll just end up feeling worse when we get home.
I’m sure that she hates me.
She probably already hates me!
You love your sister, right?
It’s because you love her that you don’t want to disappoint her, right?
How is that love—?
Then, do you hate her?
I don’t hate her! No way!
She is strict, but…
Yeah, she does have a nice side.
When I got a cold, and my mom and dad were away on business,
the person who stayed beside me the whole night, holding my hand…
It’ll be all right.
I was so happy.
She does love her sister after all.
Let’s go home.
I don’t know how to keep your sister from getting angry,
but I think you should still tell her.
Because you did your best.
That’s all that matters. That’s it.
That’s right. As long as you’ve tried, that’s enough.
I’m sure your sister will understand.
Onee-chan?! Why are you here?
I wonder why?
I’m going to tell my sister the truth.
I’m going to tell her that I didn’t get the carrots.
Because I tried my best.
Yes. That sounds good.
I’m home.
Onee-sama, I’m sorry.
Yes?
I couldn’t buy them.
I tried my hardest, but I still didn’t get the carrots.
I’m sorry.
It’s okay.
I know you tried your hardest.
Also, I’m glad you told me the truth.
Wait!
It’s great that you’re back on good terms with your sister.
Yes, thank you for everything.
You’re welcome.
Hey, we can get along too, if you want.
I mean, it’s okay if we become friends.
Ginko!
Coming, Onee-sama!
I think I can understand how Ginko-chan feels.
Hmm?
Little sisters…
Eh? Ah, what? What about little sisters?
Nothing at all! Nothing.
Little sisters love their big sisters.
That’s why we’ll even tell them lies to keep them from hating us.
No matter what type of sisterly relationship,
even if we don’t understand each other yet,
we still hope that we can
live a peaceful life together.
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo “fuwari” naderu
おてこを“ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agarou
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
Binbou   Shimai Monogatari
Tomorrow is your open house.
I’m looking forward to going.
Onee-chan, you don’t have to come.
Poor Sisters’ Story:
“A day of Perfume, Asu, and Open House”.
Please watch it!