It’s done!
For lack of a budget, I just shaped and cooled some melted chocolate.
I wonder if she’ll like it.
Valentine’s day chocolate!
I really want to hurry up and give it to her!
Yamada Kyou.
Yes!
I did it!
Despite sleeping in class…
Onee-chan!
Mom went to heaven the year Asu was born.
Dad disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room,
dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes…
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when I’m on the verge of tears,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of Jealousy,
Chocolates, and Valentines
No problem! Just leave it to me!
That’s what she said, doing her best while
simultaneously working and attending school.
Even though it’s really tough on her,
she never loses her bright smile.
This is the first time I’ve
ever made chocolate for her.
I wonder how I should give it to her?
Thank you for everything—
I guess that sounds a little strange.
It’s 3:30?
All right, then! I’ll go meet her!
You’re not here yet, Onee-chan?
Maybe she left school already?
Please accept this!
Um… about that…
This chocolate… please accept it!
Please read the letter inside! Please!
Bye, then!
Onee-chan, there’s someone you like?
What should I do?
This chocolate…
I’m home!
I’m starving!
I wonder what’s for dinner tonight!
It’s okay for Onee-chan to have someone she likes, right?
Asu?
Asu!
What’s wrong? You’re acting oddly.
No, it’s nothing at all!
Really?
Ah, here, let me help you with those.
I’m fine. I can do it myself.
Nah, here, let me.
I said I’m fine!
Asu…
S-Sorry. It’s fine, I can really do this by myself.
Please go and get some rest.
Okay, Asu, if you say so, but…
I can’t give it to her anymore, can I?
The chocolate…
Hey, did you catch yesterday’s soccer game?
Yeah, man!
It was awesome!
They managed to pull off another win.
The guy that Onee-chan likes…
That call, though!
Kind of dirty, if you ask me!
What kind of person is he?
As her younger sister, I have to find out.
I’m home!
Asu hasn’t come home yet.
Aha—ehehe… welcome home.
There’s a club meeting tomorrow, right?
Yes, that’s right.
Let’s do our best.
See you guys!
Later! See you tomorrow!
It seems like he has plenty of friends.
Good bye.
He’s carrying the bag for that old lady.
Ah, he’s even helping her up the stairs.
He… might be a good person.
But, but, but! It’s too early to be sure!
I can’t just hand Onee-chan over like that!
He’s giving up his seat for that pregnant woman!
He found a wallet on the street and immediately took it to the police!
He caught the balloon that the boy lost and he’s returning it!
Ah, he’s giving directions to a lost foreigner.
No way! This still isn’t enough!
I don’t believe it! There’s just—somehow, he seems fishy!
I’ll definitely find out just what that something is!
Cans
Bottles
Ah, he even took the time to recycle that can instead of throwing it away!
That’s just going too far!
The neighboring town.
If it’s for the sake of meat,
we’ll travel to the end of
the world!
Meat!
Walk between two stations
instead of taking the train and
buy meat with the money you save!
He really is a good person…
It’s no wonder Onee-chan fell for him.
What am I doing?
What? Onee-chan?
I-I’m home.
Welcome home.
What’s this?
I stumbled across it!
You’ve been acting strangely since yesterday, so I was wondering about what’s bothering you.
I bet this chocolate has something to do with it.
Hey, hey, who are you gonna give it to?
Could it be me?
Onee-chan, you don’t want any chocolate from me, do you?
Huh?
Yesterday.
You gave chocolate to that boy, didn’t you?
Asu, you saw that?
Some day…
Some day you’ll leave here to go live with him,
leaving me.
You don’t need my chocolate, right?!
Asu!
Onee-chan…
Onee-chan won’t accept my chocolate.
Maybe I’ll never be able to
give her chocolate again.
Even if she accepted my chocolate,
and she said she was really happy to get it,
it wouldn’t be the thing that
truly makes her happy any more.
Because Onee-chan has somehow managed to find someone who she likes even more than me.
I’m just getting in her way.
Asu.
What I should really be doing is cheering her on.
Why do I feel this way?
Ah, that’s him.
I wonder who he’s waiting for?
Could it be? Onee-chan?
Why… with another girl?
Why?
Asu!
Onee-chan!
Thank goodness! So this is where you were.
Th-Thank you.
H-Hey, Onee-chan!
Earlier, over there…
Um, er… there…
Pork buns!
Th-Th-That’s right! Pork buns!
Earlier, I saw a store over there with Pork Buns on sale for 10 yen apiece!
10 yen?! Where? Where was it?
Oh no! I made them way too cheap!
If we don’t hurry up, they might sell out!
Where was it?
Um… It was…
That way!
Roger that! It’s that way!
Asu, let’s go!
Where is it, Asu?
Er… Huh… Where was it…?
Maybe they already sold out…
What?! No way…
I wanted to eat them together with you.
If she finds out that the guy she likes already has a girlfriend,
Onee-chan will probably be really sad.
No way.
If he’s the type to accept one girl’s chocolate and then go off holding another girl’s hand,
it’s probably better if she
doesn’t get along with him.
Ah! Uh… Onee-chan, here it is!
Special Sale
Amazing Value
One Pork Bun
Until the end of February
Wow! The 10 yen pork buns!
Eh?
Special Sale
Amazing Value
One Pork Bun
Until the end of February
Ah! 10 yen! You were right!
You’re amazing, Onee-chan… You actually found them.
What are you talking about? You’re
the amazing one for finding them earlier!
Ah! Anyway, let’s hurry up and go in!
Please, just walk past the store while we’re inside!
Welcome!
Um… are these pork buns really 10 yen each?
Yes, ma’am. They’re part of a promotional campaign.
Would you like to buy one?
Two, please.
But if she were to see him holding hands
with someone else or something like that,
Onee-chan probably wouldn’t like him anymore.
That means I’d—
For her sake… There is something I can do!
Onee-chan!
What is it, Asu?
Onee-chan, it’s the perfect chance!
Let’s buy two more pork buns!
That way each of us can have two!
That’s great! The two of you are getting along well!
I ran away without giving an explanation, so I was worried things wouldn’t turn out well.
I see, I see!
I’m really happy too!
Great, great!
If you ever need help again, tell me.
Sure! Thank you!
You see, I was asked to give him
that chocolate on her behalf.
S-So that’s what happened.
I jumped to conclusions and made a big
deal out of nothing. How embarrassing.
I’m sorry it caused a misunderstanding.
But, you know, Asu,
if you’re worried that something like that
might happen in the future, remember this:
I will never abandon you.
Ever!
Yes.
That said, I think the fact that you
were so jealous made me a little happy.
What is it? What’s wrong?
I don’t care.
Sorry, sorry! Are you mad?
Hey, don’t leave me behind!
It’s things like worrying about someone else,
bringing along a coat to protect them from the cold,
and searching for cheap pork buns just so
you’ll be able to eat them together.
When I think that one day, Onee-chan will do these things with someone other than me,
I can’t help but feel a little sad.
I imagine that even when that time comes,
Onee-chan will assure me I won’t be left alone.
But is that something I can just agree with?
Maybe, when that time comes…
By the way, Asu.
Who was this chocolate intended for?
My favorite person!
Huh?! Who’s that?!
Wait up, Asu!
Who is your favorite person?
When that time comes, I’ll definitely choose whatever makes my favorite sister happy.
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo “fuwari” naderu
おてこを“ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agarou
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
Binbou   Shimai Monogatari
I hear a voice that sounds like a ghost, Asu!
I-It’ll be okay! I’m here with you!
Poor Sisters’ Story:
“A Day of Guitars, Dreams, and a Music Teacher”.
Please watch it!