Kyou-chan, you're already a big sister, aren't you?
Yes!
I'm your big sister! Do you understand me?
She can definitely hear you.
Back then, mom was still alive, and dad was kind. Back then.
Say, Kyou-chan...
What is it?
I have a favor to ask of you.
Back then, I made a promise to mom.
A very important promise.
Onee-chan! Onee-chan!
Are you okay?
Oh, I'm fine.
I wonder if your fever is gone yet.
I'm fine!
My temperature is the same as yours, so that means it's gone!
I'm going to go deliver the newspapers.
O-Onee-chan!
Leave it to me!
Onee-chan, don't go out there.
You can't.
Because you went on your newspaper run during rainy days, your cold got even worse.
Don't worry! It's all about mind over matter!
Onee-chan, you should really stay in bed!
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
A Day of Colds, Promises and Mother
Onee-chan, the rice porridge is done!
Thanks, Asu.
It's still hot, so be careful, okay?
Delicious!
It really is delicious.
You've still got an appetite so I'm sure you'll be fine.
Asu, aren't you going to eat?
Y-Yeah...
I'm not hungry yet.
I see.
You've been sweating, so I'll have to wash you down and dry you off.
It's hot.
Is that okay? Do you need more ice?
No, it's fine, Asu.
As long as you get lots of rest, I'm sure you'll get better in no time.
It's kind of nice to catch a cold every now and then.
No, no! I have to hurry up and get better!
I can't continue making Asu worry like this.
Yes! I've made a complete recovery.
Well, you had me worried! I'm glad you're better.
It's all thanks to my little sister's care.
It's good to be back at work.{
I finally beat that cold!
For Asu's sake, I have to work extra hard and make up for all the time I took off!
Huh? She's not here?
I'm home! Asu?
The faucet is running?
What's happened?
Asu?
Asu! Asu!
W-What are you doing?
Mr. Landlord! Asu...We have to get Asu to the hospital!
Onee-chan...
What's wrong, Asu? Are you cold?
There's no way you can just carry her there.
Calm down. I'll call an ambulance.
Yes!
How could I not have noticed?
Asu had also come down with a cold.
But she still took care of me... Until she collapsed.
Mom.
It's alright, Kyou-chan. I just have a cold.
That was the last thing that mom said before her ambulance drove away.
After she got sick, she never came back from the hospital.
She'll have to stay here as a patient for a while.
I understand. Please take care of her.
This is troublesome.
If her older sister doesn't leave, we won't be able to...
I'm sorry. Can you please just let her stay by the bed just for tonight?
I'm sorry, Asu. I'm sorry.
I want to be strong!
I want to be a big sister who can take away Asu's worries!
Mom...!
Say, Kyou-chan...
What is it?
I have a favor to ask of you.
Please protect your sister.
Okay! I'll protect her!
I'll always be there to protect her!
I made that promise.
Even though I promised back then that I'd protect Asu,
I wasn't able to do anything!
Onee-chan?
Asu!
I'm sorry I made you worr--
Same here. I'm sorry for not noticing you were sick until after you collapsed.
Sorry.
This time, I'll look after you, okay?
She's made it past the worst of it, so you shouldn't have anything to worry about.
Thank you very much.
At this point, we need to run a number of different tests, so leave it to us, okay?
Okay.
Nice and easy, okay?
Asu.
I'm home.
Oh yeah, I wonder if Asu would like to eat an apple.
I...really can't do anything.
When Asu isn't here, I can't do anything!
Mom, I can't protect Asu like this!
There's just no way!
Hunger is the world's best seasoning.
If we wait just a little longer, it'll taste so much more deliicious...
Time, turn back! The food has passed its expiration date!
Onee-chan, good morning!
Good morning, Asu.
How are you feeling?
Is it okay that you're already up?
I'm feeling a lot better than I did yesterday.
That's great.
Ah, that's right.
I peeled an apple for you.
You did?
Onee-chan, you didn't soak them in salt water first, did you?
Let's eat!
It's tasty!
I'm sorry.
I'm so bad at everything...
Onee-chan.
How is she doing?
Ah, Mr. Landlord.
Good morning!
I'm feeling a lot better.
Thank you very much for yesterday.
Leave the rest to me and get back to school.
Oh... Okay.
Onee-chan, take care.
I'll see you soon.
Kyou-chan, please protect your sister.
Okay! I'll protect her!
I'll always be there to protect her!
I thought it might help you feel better, so I brought along my guitar.
Yamada Asu
Don't tell me you're planning on singing in here!
Well, that was the idea, but it seems like maybe it wasn't such a good one.
This is a hospital, you know! They'll throw us out!
You think so?
But I'd love to hear Ichinokura-san's song.
Somehow, I feel like it'd help me get better.
Well then, I'll sing because you said so, okay?
Onee-chan is late, huh?
Dandelions...
Oh yeah...
These are Mom's favorite flowers!
I'll take some to Mom in the hospital.
Mom always smiles when she sees dandelions!
That's why, if I bring them to her, she'll get better again!
Back then, I would gather flowers day after day.
Mom! Mom! I brought you some more flowers!
Back then...
There was nothing I could do.
Nothing.
Kyou, you brought me some dandelions again, didn't you?
Mom.
There's nothing I can do!
Even though I promised, I can't...
Thank you.
Looking at the dandelions you've brought me always helps me forget about my sickness.
Mom...
Mom's smile... She looks so happy.
Hey, mom!
Why do you smile whenever you see dandelions?
You see, it's because the dandelions look so happy and carefree to me.
They look happy?
Yes.
That's why they remind me of you, Kyou-chan.
Me?
Yes.
Just like the dandelions, you always seem to be smiling.
That's why I smile whenever I see dandelions.
Really?
That's right. Mom wasn't smiling because she was looking at the dandelions...
She was looking at me.
She was smiling because she saw my smile.
Mom was...
Looking...
At me.
Even so, I...
Even so, I never smiled for Asu.
For Asu.
Onee-chan.
Onee-chan, don’t try to take anybody else’s place.
Asu.
You’re my older sister. Stay that way.
Okay, I will. I'll be right here for you.
I'm not going anywhere.
I... What the heck was I doing? I...
Asu!!
I'd forgotten!
The thing that only I can do for Asu. The most important thing.
I wonder if Onee-chan is okay.
I hope she hasn't tired herself out worrying about me.
We'll have to handle the hospital fees, too. Maybe I'm just being an annoyance to her.
O-Onee-chan!
Good night, Asu! Get well soon!
O-Onee-chanQ
Thank you.
Onee-chan!
Thank you!
Onee-chan's smiling face...
It looks just like a dandelion!
Congratulations on being discharged, Asu-chan.
Thank you very much.
Make sure to take it easy for a while, okay?
Okay.
Thank you for all you've done.
Hey, Onee-chan, there's a place I'd like to go.
Hey, don't push yourself too much, okay?
Okay.
But, at first, your cold was far worse than mine.
I was so worried about you that I forgot to take care of myself.
Asu.
Ah, here it is.
Here?
This place is...
Right here, Mom asked me to do something.
It was a long time ago, but this is where I heard it.
I'm your big sister! Do you understand me?
Onee-chan's voice.
Along with Mom's voice.
I ask you, please...
Protect... Your big sister.
Your big sister...
Please protect her, she said.
But, Asu, Mom...
No, I don't remember this at all, but I get the feeling that that was what I heard.
That's why I've promised!
Yes! I'll protect her!
I will protect Onee-chan!
Mother, it's all right.
We're keeping our promises.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
Wow! Onee-chan, look, look!
Wow, they're in full bloom!
We're very happy together!
Onee-chan, this is bad! Really bad!
The sakura-viewing has come inside!