HEY BUDDY MAKE SURE ALL THE NARRATIVE SECTIONS ARE IN THE SAME TENSE OKAY THANKS MAN. ALSO MAKE SURE THAT YOU DECIDE WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO END UP DOING WITH HONORIFICS
Our parents are no longer here.
Because of that, Asu and I have to do our best on our own.
Sometimes it's difficult, but the two of us still pull through.
Up to this point, we've been able to live our lives this way.
This month's bills are going to put us in a bit of a pinch, huh?
Yes, it'll be a pinch.
Spring, which will bring this sakura tree into bloom is still far away,
and a harsh winter is right around the corner.
We don't have anyone to protect us from the cold.
There isn't anyone who understands that type of coldness.
That's what I think.
That said...
Yes.
That said,
we won't lose!
Onee-chan, the landlord is looking at the sakura tree.
Ah, you're right.
Let's try asking him for an extension, one last time.
I wonder if that's really alright.
We've already asked him so many times.
He'll probably just tell us no again.
We'll worry about that when it happens.
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
So, we were left behind.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
A Day of the Apartment, Sakura, and Moving
Mr. Landlord!
Eriko...
Mami...
Ah, uh-what do you want?
Um...
Um, can we please postpone this month's rent payment until I get my paycheck?
Oh, sure. I don't mind.
We're saved.
But he was acting kind of strange, don't you think?
Yeah. I wonder who Eriko-san and Nami-san are.
What was the landlord looking at?
Just what did he see?
I'm home!
Asu, I got my paycheck!
Welcome home, onee-chan.
Here.
Thank you for all your work.
I also got paid for my tutoring job,
So we should have a little left over this month.
That's great, Onee-chan!
First of all, since the landlord was nice enough to wait this long, we need to take care of last month's rent.
After that, since I have tomorrow off, why don't we go somewhere together?
Ok.
Where should we go?
Anywhere is fine.
Let's keep thinking about it until tomorrow.
Sure.
Asu,
have you thought of any place you really want to go?
Nope. Have you?
Not yet.
I'm still thinking.
Ahh. Seems like staying at home is the best after all.
Isn't it?
ARA?!?!
What is it?
Over there.
Where?
Over there, over there.
Onee-chan, that's...
Yeah, it's blooming!
It's already evening, onee-chan.
So it is.
But at least today was a good chance to just relax. It was nice, wasn't it?
Yeah, it was.
Hey, onee-chan, let's go to the bath early tonight.
Sure! You want to go now?
Well then, let's just take long and relaxing baths.
Sure! Let's go.
Bath House Hawaii
Welco--
Hmmm? What's wrong? Kyou-chan, Asu-chan!
The two of you don't look so well.
What happened, Kyou-chan?
Obasan, we're going to be evicted from our apartment!
What do you mean?
Mr. Landlord, good evening.
We're heading over to the bathhouse.
I see.
That aside, you two--can you move out of the apartment?
I said, move out of the apartment.
Wh-why?
I paid last month's rent yesterday!
There's really no time, so hurry up and leave.
No way...
If you make us leave, we won't have anywhere to live!
I'm telling you to leave.
Contract
So that's what happened...
Onee-chan, do we really have to move out?
We don't have a choice. We can't keep being a bother to the landlord.
I guess renting a room to the two of us ended up being troublesome for the landlord after all.
But, hey! We'll worry about that when it happens, right, Asu?
You're right, onee-chan.
The two of us just need to keep giving it our all.
There's no way we're going to be beaten!
Right!
When spring comes, we won't be able to watch the sakura tree from this room.
I came across some news by means of a rumor.
It seems like they're going to build a luxury mansion complex here.
What? They're going to tear this apartment down just to build a luxury mansion complex?
That seems to be the case.
So that's why the landlord is making us leave.
He hasn't said anything to me yet, but it seems I should start packing too.
Onee-chan, will this sakura tree be cut down, too?
If they're building a mansion, it probably will.
Now that I think about it, the landlord was gazing at this tree.
he was probably doing it because his precious tree is going to get cut down.
Bean sprouts for breakfast,
bean sprouts for lunch,
and bean sprouts for dinner.
The longer you boil the noodles,
the bigger they get.
Sawa Real Estate
Asu, this house looks like it's pretty big and comfortable.
You're right.
Apartment for Rent
Rent: 42000 yen a month
Faces south, nice and sunny. Just a two minute walk to the station!
Ah, this looks pretty good too.
Yeah, there're a lot of options.
Yes, and it seems like there are plenty affordable ones with enough room for both of us.
Closet
Storage
6-mat western style room
4-mat Japanese style room
Veranda
That's right.
Hey, you two.
If you'd like, there're many more ads inside for you to consider.
Eh?
Ah, um...
Sorry, but we're fine for today!
Onee-chan, is there really no way to stop them from tearing down the apartment?
If that's what the landlord has decided, there's nothing we can do about it.
I don't want to leave.
I want to watch the flowers bloom there next year.
It was strange to hear Asu say something that sounded selfish.
But I felt the same way.
I suppose we were both being selfish.
I'm not sure why,
but looking at all the newer, bigger apartments and imagining how wonderful living in them would be,
for some reason, I couldn't enjoy it.
All I could think about was how nice it would be if we could keep living at our old apartment
Onee-chan!
The landlord always seems troubled when we're around...
We should leave.
Ok.
We need to hurry up and find a new place to live, Asu.
Kyo-chan! Asu-chan!
Hello!
Carrying all that luggage!
You're looking for somewhere to live, right?
Eh? Well, yes.
If so, then don't worry about a thing.
It just so happens that the second floor of my house is unoccupied.
Are you serious?
Hey now, wait a minute.
Yeah, hold on now.
Kyo-chan and Asu-chan are going to live on my second floor.
No way! My house is bigger and cleaner!
Well, uhm--I won't even charge you rent!
What? What's this all about?
Yeah! Just what are you thinking?
You listen here, Asu-chan and Kyou-chan will be living on my second floor, and moreover...
Somehow, it seems like everyone has heard that we have to move out of the apartment.
Um, everyone, why do you all know that we have to...
Uhm, eh... well... about that--
The truth is, I was asked by Hayashi-san.
Me too.
By the landlord!?
Why does the landlord care about where the two of us--
Hayashi-san might not say anything,
but he worries about the two of you like you 're his own grandchildren.
It's all because of what happened to Eriko-san and Mami-chan, I bet.
Those names...
Eriko...! Mami...!
They were Hayashi-san's wife and granddaughter.
We always thought the landlord lived alone!
It was a long time ago.
He lost them in an accident.
It's been forty years since then.
It was a terrible tragedy
The driver was in a huge truck.
He was never a man of many words,
but nobody has seen him so much as laugh or even smile since that day.
The three of them would always happily watch the sakura bloom.
Watching the sakura...
That sakura tree must be very important to the landlord.
That's why the landlord would stare at the sakura tree so intently.
So that's how it was.
If we don't do something to stop the new complex from being built...
Onee-chan, let's go!
Asu!
Obaa-san! Can you please keep these bags for the time being?
We'll come back for them soon!
Hey, w-wait, you two!
Everyone, we're sorry, but thank you for your trouble.
Asu, let's go back to the apartment.
All this time, I thought that you and I were all alone, Asu.
So I thought that as long as we were together, it wouldn't matter where we were living.
Onee-chan!
But when the landlord kicked us out,
While we were looking for a new place to stay, I realized something.
I really love that apartment! When I think about it being torn down, I realize it even more!
Yeah!
I want to live there forever!
Me too, Onee-chan!
Construction's already started?!
Are we too late?
Mr. Landlord!
Wh-why are you two here?
Please don't let them tear down the apartment!
The sakura tree! Don't cut down the sakura tree!
No way!
Mr. Landlord! Why?!
I don't plan on having the apartment torn down, you know.
Huh? But just now--
Onee-chan, it looks like the one being torn down is the building next door.
You're right.
As you can see, this wasn't the one that got sold.
So the apartment is going to stay like it is?
Well then, why did you tell us to move out?
Since next door has become a construction zone,
there's bound to be a lot of traffic.
It's too dangerous.
It was a terrible tragedy
The driver was in a huge truck.
You've already found a new place to live, right?
Don't come back here anymore.
That's right.
The landlord is always looking out for us.
Two years ago, he was the only one who would rent us a room, even though we had no parents.
Asu.
Onee-chan.
We won't move!
We love this apartment, the sakura tree, and you, Mr. Landlord.
B-But still...
We'll be very careful of the cars.
When spring comes, I really want to watch the sakura blossoms together with you, Mr. Landlord!
Please!
Fine. Suit yourself.
Hooray!
Ah! Onee-chan, look!
See the two flowers that blossomed before springtime?
The landlord put a little enclosure around them to protect them from the wind.
He really did!
Those flowers are just like us.
The landlord is protecting  of us.
That's right.
The landlord is definitely protecting us.
Asu, it looks like we have a little extra money left over this month.
Is there somewhere you'd like to go?
Yes.
Where?
I want to go to this apartment and stay there with onee-chan.
This apartment is the best!
That sounds good to me.
The spring that will bring the sakura tree into full bloom is still far away,
and before that comes a harsh winter.
Even though our parents are gone, there is still someone out there who will protect us from the cold.
There is someone who can understand that coldness.
Watching the sakura tree from the window of this apartment,
the two of us are definitely not alone.
This is what I've realized.
Feelings you want to share;
feelings you cannot share,
no matter how kind and gentle those feelings are.
Poor Sisters' Story:
A Day of Loneliness, Ginko, and Onee-sama.
Please watch it!