Big winner!
Congratulations!
I've won?
That's right, the third place prize.
Let's see... third place gets... which one was it again...
Oh, this one!
Here, the highest quality kind, and it comes as a set.
You're happy, right?
Thinking about it afterwards...
This must be a present given to Asu and I from Mother in heaven.
I'm back.
Welcome back, Onee-chan. Thank you for your work.
Breakfast is ready.
Thank you...
I'm really tired...
Sorry.
That's fine. It's all right, Onee-chan.
I guess I was a little careless.
That's no good.
I'm going to go wash my face.
Onee-chan.
Yawning in front of our house is kind of rude, isn't it?
No, that's not what I mean.
It's fine, it's fine.
See you, Onee-chan will go on ahead.
Hey, be careful and watch out for cars!
Okay, I'll be fine.
I let Asu worry about me again.
I have to try harder.
Lately, the neighboring district's newspaper carrier resigned.
Because they haven't found anyone yet, the work has been tough lately.
Hey, Asu.
I forgot to tell Asu that
this morning's cucumber was great.
The third place prize!
Congratulations, Asu-chan.
Third place receives this, and it comes as a set.
Prepaid premium cell phones.
The card is already in there.
Here, let me help you bag it up.
Are... are you really giving me this?
Of course.
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Father left a huge debt after gambling and is now missing,
leaving only the two of us.
The place we live in is
a beaten up 40 year old apartment with one room and no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
Omoitei modorenai kara
Even though we can't return to our memories,
Kyou wo ikii asuotsukamo
let's seize today and search for tomorrow.
Hitorimo ochimo hitorikiri janai
I may be by myself, but I'm not alone.
Futarimo ochimo futarikimi janai
Even if it's only the two of us, we're not alone.
Soredemokoboreru namida no mae ni
Even when seeing my tears about to fall,
Egao nashi ugokyuu dekiru noka nai
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Omoitei modorenai kara
Even though we can't return to our memories
Kyou wo ikii asuotsukamo
let's seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kagega eno naikimi no owoseki wa kokoro ni aru
That unreachable jewel is there within your heart.
Mukai kaze ni shingokyuu
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
A Day of Emotions, Uneasiness, and Cell Phones.
Eh? Asu, what are these?
The shopping district was having a raffle...
These are real, right? Onee-chan.
Onee-chan?
Cell... Phones?
When you say "cell" you mean "mobile" right?
I've always thought that these things can only be had in some far off world...
No... you're exaggerating.
Then it's a dream?
I don't think so...
In any case, how do we use this?
Let me see... first, you turn it on.
Is it here?
Where, where?
And then...
Then you choose the payment method. This card has 3000 yen and works for three months.
3000 yen?
Look, that's what it says.
Insert the number, eh?
And then...
We can use it now, just like that?
Onee-chan, try calling me.
O-okay.
It's ringing!
Hello.
Yes, yes.
Can you hear me now?
Did you hang up?
That was dangerous.
Why?
Calling like that uses up money.
3000 yen, eh? We'll have to use it only for important matters.
Oh yeah, that's right.
Are you okay, Onee-chan?
I did it again... Yes, I'm fine.
And today, I have this.
If something happens, make sure you call Onee-chan as fast as you can.
You too, Onee-chan.
I'll go on ahead now.
Today I'm drowsy again.
I forgot it again today...
to tell Asu that her tofu miso soup was very good.
Oh yeah, I have to turn off the cell phone when in school.
Eh?
What are you doing?
Ginko-chan, good morning.
Good morning.
Eh? You bought a cell phone?
This? No... It's a prize from the shopping district.
Prize...
Onee-sama has a much better cell phone than that.
Once I'm in middle school, I'll buy one that's as great as Onee-sama's.
You should listen when others are talking. What are you doing anyway?
I forgot how to turn this off... what should I do?
You don't even know about that? Just press here.
Ginko-chan, you're so great! Thank you.
I see Onee-sama do that a lot, so of course I know.
If you have anything else that you don't understand, just ask me.
All right, thank you. Well then.
That's nice... a cell pohne.
Asu hasn't called yet, eh?
I wonder if I should call her...
Onee-chan hasn't called yet, eh?
Maybe I should call her.
No, no. It's too wasteful.
Wait a minute, maybe something really big happened.
When that happens, I'll need to use the cell phone.
If I just call her like that, I'll probably run out of minutes when I really need it.
Why don't you call? If you want to, just call her.
Yeah, you're right...
So that's the mentality of a poor person, eh?
It's been a week already.
Yeah.
And we didn't even use it once.
If the three months pass just like that...
That means we've wasted even more money.
Okay. Let's use it more freely afterwards.
Y... Yeah.
But, don't waste it too much. When we need it...
Onee-chan, if you think like that, you won't call.
That's right...
Ah, the night papers...
I have to concentrate. Wake up.
Turn on, OK.
Yamada-san.
Yes?
Can you help me for a sec?
Okay.
Onee-chan didn't pick up. School should have let out already.
I wonder if something happened...
Ah, Ginko-chan.
So you finally decided to call.
Yeah, because Onee-chan said to use it more freely.
I wanted to ask her whether she wanted curry or stewed meat for dinner.
Calling for such a matter is so boring.
Oh yeah, Ginko-chan. if you want, you should give me a call.
Your number... Well, I guess I will when I feel like it.
Anyway, what happened to Onee-chan?
She must be really tired. I'm so worried.
(Our only goal is the before closing sale.)
(On paydays we can have a luxurious dinner with three side dishes.)
You can't reach her?
Yeah, it's strange.
Connection problems?
I'm not sure...
When I was at home I could connect to her.
Well then,
let me try to place a call to my sister.
Eh?
Here, let me borrow it.
Uh...
Hello?
Onee-sama, it's Ginko.
Yes, sorry to give you a call so suddenly.
Are you doing okay right now?
Yes, yes. That's right, Onee-sama.
I heard it was won from a shopping distric raffle.
Amazing.
Yes, I think it's the third place prize.
Yes.
If only I can be this carefree on a cell phone...
Yes, thank you very much.
Yes.
This isn't a time to get emotional.
Ah ...um... Ginko-chan.
If you speak for that long,
uh... the 3000 yen will run out.
She can't hear me at all.
Um...
Yes, that's right, Onee-sama. And I...
Oh yeah, Onee-chan has been really tired lately. She doesn't say much.
Ah, yes.
It's great that Ginko-chan can talk about so much.
Yamada-san, thank you.
Okay.
Eh? What?
Ah, there was a missed call.
It must be Asu.
Eh? It's busy?
Yes, it's the tissue paper from the shopping district.
Yes.
Ah, yes.
You turn the corner at the cigarette store, right?
Um...
Yes, that's right.
Well then, later, Onee-sama.
Thank you.
Onee-chan called, eh?
It's Asu!
Hello, Asu?
Ah, Onee-chan-
Asu?
Asu, what's wrong?
What's wrong?
It hung up.
Looks like it ran out of battery.
Um...
It must be because you didn't charge it fully, so it ran out so fast.
The number you have called is not available right now...
I can't connect... what's wrong?
Did something happen?
The number you have called is not...
Ah, Onee-chan-
Something must have happened.
She must be at the shopping district at this time.
Excuse me! I'll be right back.
I wonder if Onee-chan needed something...
When she left this morning she looked a little drowsy.
Maybe she's not feeling well?
If you want to charge the battery you can come to my house...
Eh? Where did she go?
Normally she'll be at the newspaper route's start off point.
Eh, Kyo-chan? Now that you mention it, she's not here right now.
Eh? She's not here? Did she come?
Boss! What should we do with this?
Oh, I'm coming.
Um...
Onee-chan really didn't feel well... where can she...
Oh yeah, that voice from before was Kyo-chan...
And she's gone.
Asu-chan? I haven't see her today.
Is that so...
Now that you mention it, she should've been here by now.
Thank you very much.
Eh?
That's strange... Asu won't purposely hang up on me ike that.
Don't tell me...
She got kidnapped?
Onee-chan, where did you go?
Don't tell me that she didn't feel well and went home?
The number you have called is not available...
Asu!
Onee-chan!
The number you called...
Geez!
Onee-chan, Onee-chan, where are you!?
Onee-chan, Onee-chan!
Onee-chan...
Onee-chan!
Wow, when we finally have cell phones, why doesn't she use it now?
Onee-chan!!!
Asu!
Asu!!!
Onee-chan!
Asu!
Thank goodness! Onee-chan doesn't fall down easily.
Asu too. You weren't kidnapped.
Eh?
Thank goodness...
Onee-chan.
What? The reason I couldn't connect was because your battery ran out?
Yeah... along with some other things.
I was also away during that time.
It was just a chance happening, but it was so tiring.
You're right.
Oh yeah, that call from before, what were you about to say?
Eh? Ah, that... I wanted to ask if you wanted curry or stewed meat for dinner...
That was it?
Sorry.
Stewed meat, then.
Okay.
Who is it?
Hello.
Oh, she's here.
Ah, Ginko-chan?
You found your Onee-san, right?
Yes.
That's great, I was worried.
Um... that...
Sorry for using your phone.
Did I trouble you?
No... not really.
Oh yeah, I also have a cell phone now.
I see... that's great.
Well then, see you tomorrow.
Bye-bye.
Ginko-chan also has a cell phone now.
That's great.
Yes.
O... Onee-chan... the night newspaper run...
You also brought the bicycle out...
Anyway, try your best!
I'll make delicious stewed meat for you!
Onee-chan, are you all right?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Ah... I forgot to tell Asu that the omelettes were delicious.
Hello. Onee-chan?
Ah, Asu, that...
What's up? Is something wrong? Did something happen...
The omelettes for breakfast... were really delicious.
Eh?
That's it.
That's what I wanted to tell you, Asu.
Thank you for everything as always, Asu.
Don't try too hard, Onee-chan.
Although it was just a small thing,
these cell phones must have been a present from Mother in heaven.
They're probably telling me not to worry too much.
Mother... and Asu.
Sorry, you didn't win.
Well, you've already tried fifty times in a row.
I know how hard you've been trying, just what did you want?
The cell phones from the third place prize.
Onee-sama, we don't have any more tickets for the raffle.
Well then, go buy some things to redeem tickets.
Yes.
Mister, I still want to try.
Onee-sama, thank you for giving me a cell phone.
But...
If you buy one normally, it will be cheaper.
Ta ainaiosha be iga
Even when everyday talk
Fuinito gi re ta tokimo
gets interrupted,
Ko oshite sobani iru dakede
all I need is you by my side,
Anshin tekiru
so I feel safe and sound.
Obekowo ruwa ni na de ru
That kind face of yours
Soyokaze ni tai ne
is just like a gentle wind.
Gyuto gyuto te to te wo tsunaitara
We tightly hold each other's hands,
Sakamichi wo kage a ga ra wo
and run up that hilly path together.
Ashita wa zettai tanoshiine
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Nara n de yuko o
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Gyuto gyuto kaze wo tsu kama e tara
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Ryuote hirogeto doketai
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Gyuto gyuto ashita no asa atemo
We tightly hold each other's hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Nara n de yuko iisho ni yuko o
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Asu, do you still remember Mother?
I remember we had a promise.
Binbou Shimai Monogatari.
A Day of Colds, Promises and Mother
Please watch it!