What should we do, Onee-chan?
The dark lord of riches is coming!
Don’t worry!
Onee-chan will chase him away!
Pay your rent!
Rent
Here.
Onee-chan...
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
So, we were left behind.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when seeing my tears about to fall,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of the Landlord,
a Watermelon, and a Hospital Visit
The soft feeling of a futon that has been aired out in the sun.
It's flat like a rice cracker but ever so fluffy.
As usual, my younger sister is busily preparing a delicious dinner.
I like this natural routine more than anything else.
But...
That’s right.
Today at 7:30 p.m., the dark lord of riches will make his monthly visit.
Onee-chan, are you okay?!
Yeah, don’t worry.
I’m fine, I’m fine.
Thank you for the meal.
What should we do?
If we pay this month’s rent, the next month will be hard on us.
But the landlord won’t give us a break, will he?
When we eat dinner, we try to avoid the subject of money.
This has been our unwritten rule for a long time.
But today is an exception.
Onee-chan, today I will protect you from the scary demon!
It’s okay, Asu. Onee-chan will try her best.
He’s coming.
He’s coming!
Huh?
He didn’t come...
Does that mean this month’s rent payment is canceled?
I don’t think it’s that simple...
He must not be collecting the rent this month.
Onee-chan...
That feels good!
Onee-chan, you’re certainly in a good mood.
Yeah!
Without a doubt, the landlord must have decided to not collect the rent anymore.
That’s why I’m feeling so great!
Why do you think that?
He probably won the lottery or something, so he doesn’t need to collect rent anymore.
That’s why he didn’t come by last night.
Maybe we won’t have to pay the rent ever again!
I don’t think things will go that well...
Hey, look, look.
I’m wearing my swimsuit under my t-shirt.
This way, it doesn’t matter how soaked I am.
You should go change too.
Don’t do that, Onee-chan!
Wait up!
You’re too loud!
Sorry.
N-No, it’s fine, as long as you understand.
Man.
I was so relieved when that annoying landlord didn’t come, too.
Ah, that’s right.
It was such a relief not having to pay rent this month.
What are you talking about?
The landlord didn’t come by last night saying, “Pay the rent!” right?
He must have won the lottery—
Ah, the landlord is in the hospital right now.
Eh?
He’s hospitalized?
Yeah.
I heard that he fell from somewhere and broke his leg or something.
Is he okay?
I have no idea.
He didn’t even tell anyone,
and even if someone visited him, he’d just brush them off.
Oh well, I guess it can’t be helped.
He only has himself to blame for his attitude.
No one...
Eh?
He must be lonely, with no one visiting him.
All alone...
So he didn’t win a lottery, and the rent’s not canceled.
Of course that wouldn’t happen.
I’m pretty stupid, aren’t I?
That’s what I like about you.
Asu!
But, Onee-chan, you really believed your own explanation, didn’t you?
Hey, why don’t we go visit the landlord together?
Yes, let’s go.
Isn’t it a little frightening?
Yeah, I’m a little bit afraid.
He is a dark lord after all.
When he realizes that we’ve only brought one apple...
Stop screwing around!
He’ll probably scold us.
But, we don’t have enough money to buy anything more expensive.
It can’t be helped.
Yes, it’s better than nothing.
Probably...
Yeah! I suppose...
Mr. Landlord! We’ve come to visit you!
I-Idiots!
Really.
This is a hospital, so don’t speak so loudly.
S-Sorry.
Isn’t the landlord using a loud vo—
Ah, um, your leg. Is it okay?
Does it look okay to you?
They do all these examinations, and smoking’s prohibited.
This is the worst!
Why don’t you start slicing that apple already?
Ah, yes!
Here you go.
Just put it on the side for now.
Oh, um...
It was pretty hot this morning, so I watered the yard.
You weren’t watering the yard, you were playing in the water, right?
Eh? Um, yeah, but...
I wore a swimsuit under my t-shirt, so it’s fine.
I was asking if you played with the water!
S-Sorry.
Well then, we’ll be going now.
As we expected, that was pretty scary.
Yes, but...
I wonder if he ate the apple.
I hope he did.
Hey, Onee-chan.
For tonight’s dinner, does burdock salad and seaweed scrambled eggs sound good?
Yeah! I’ll look forward to it.
Write down the answer.
Asu, go brush your teeth.
Okay.
What should I do tomorrow?
What’s wrong?
If you put
something in between
bread crusts,
it’s a sandwich.
Bread crust
Ham
If we pay the rent
for this month,
it’s going to be tight...
.
Money
I’m going!
Ah, wait.
Hmm?
Asu, I’m going to visit the landlord again today after school.
I might be home late, so don’t worry, okay?
Onee-chan...
I thought about it, and it’s just like what you said.
Anyone who was hospitalized and had no visitors would feel lonely.
If it was me, I’d feel the same.
So, I think I’ll go visit him more for the time being.
Yeah, that’s a good idea!
I’m going now!
Ah, Asu.
You don’t have to force yourself to go.
Asu?!
You see, Mrs. Yaoichi asked me to give this watermelon to the landlord.
If you’re going to visit him every day, then I will too, okay?
Asu!
W-Wait. I-It hurts, Onee-chan.
Hmm, it seems like he’s still in a bad mood.
Okay.
Good day!
What the?! You two came again?
Um, Mrs. Yaoichi asked Asu to bring this watermelon as a gift.
Even though it’s a little small, the skin’s firm, so it must be delicious.
I’ll go cut it right now.
You can eat it whenever you get hungry.
Mr. Landlord, would you like some barley tea?
I brought it from home.
It’s pretty hot today, so why don’t you cool off with this.
Here.
Ah, welcome back!
Cleaning
Thank you for delivering the watermelon, Asu-chan.
No problem.
That old man didn’t eat it, right?
Don’t mind him, he’s always like that.
Oh yeah.
Here, these are for you.
This is my thanks for making that delivery.
It’s meat, so eat a lot and cheer up.
Thanks for the food!
Amazing! We have quite a feast today!
Yes! She really gave us a lot of meat.
Delicious!
I’m truly fortunate.
No matter how depressed I am,
as long as I get to eat dinner with Asu like this,
those feelings will float away like a cloud.
And tomorrow I’ll be able to smile again.
Then I’ll definitely be able to have the energy to try my best.
I wonder how the landlord is doing.
Maybe this man who lives alone really doesn’t have anyone like we do.
Asu probably saw that in him.
Asu, why don’t we visit him every day?
Yeah, let’s do it!
Hello.
Ah, you two visit a lot, don’t you?
It must be hard to come by every day.
Not at all.
Is Mr. Landlord still sleeping?
I’m not sure. He was awake a while ago.
What the, it’s you guys again.
Mr. Landlord, I picked some flowers for you today.
Asu picked them from the roadside.
You guys don’t have to come anymore!
I said you guys don’t have to come anymore.
I think we troubled him...
Oh no, we have to prepare for the leaking!
Asu! Go get the dishes and pans!
Eh? It’s not leaking...
Did someone fix it for us?
I heard that he fell from somewhere and broke his leg or something.
Ah...
For us...
All the time, the landlord’s expression never changed.
Even when Asu was massaging his back,
or when I tried to get him to say “Ah” while feeding him pudding.
His face always had a lonely look.
But I have a feeling that he was never annoyed.
It must be hard to come by every day.
I get it! That’s why he said that!
You guys don’t have to come anymore!
Onee-chan, that reminds me.
I saw him fixing himself up as we came in.
That’s great!
I was afraid he would hate me for showing up every day.
I didn’t know what I would do if he ended up hating you too.
I’m so relieved!
Onee-chan.
Asu.
Good morning!
Mr. Landlord!
Wh-what? Didn’t I tell you guys not to come anymore?
This is our last visit.
Please get well soon, and come back to the apartment.
T-Thank you.
Today I’m wearing my swimsuit under my t-shirt again.
But on a hot day like this, swimming is still
definitely better than just playing with water.
But, Onee-chan...
This isn’t a pool...
Isn’t this a washbasin?
Don’t mind, don’t mind.
Isn’t it great to have a pool in the yard?
I can also wash your hair while we’re at it.
We’ll be scolded by the landlord again.
It’ll be fine because we’re good friends with the landlord now.
Who said we’re good friends?
Ah, Mr. Landlord.
Congratulations on being released.
Look at this mess. What were you guys thinking?
Ah, what should I do?!
Don’t say, “What should I do?!”
Ah! Sorry!
Oh yeah, and...
Pay the rent.
In the end, the landlord still collected this month’s rent.
But after that, he quietly said, “Thank you for watering the flowers”, right?
Yes.
That’s right, even though the landlord will still
transform into the dark lord of
riches on the 30th of every month.
Let’s do our best and always stay in this apartment, Asu.
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo "fuwari" naderu
おてこを”ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agara wo
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
BIG SALE!!
Pork Tenderloin
Vegetables
Green Peppers
White Radish
Onee-chan! The radishes that were on sale are sold out!
That girl... who is she?
Poor Sisters’ Story.
A Day of Carrots, Lies, and the Echigoya Sisters.
Please watch it!