This is Kyou, my elder daughter.
She’s fifteen years old.
This one is Asu, my younger daughter.
She’s only nine years old.
To ensure that she doesn’t wake her sister, Kyou
always gets up quickly when the alarm clock rings.
Every morning, Kyou leaves to deliver newspapers.
I’ll be going now.
All right!
Good morning, Asu. I can’t wait for today’s fireworks festival!
I’ve always been watching over the two of them from heaven.
I was able to leave behind just one thing for the two of you:
a small promise.
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
So, we were left behind.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is where we live.
But, when spring comes...
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
A Day of Yukatas, Fireworks,
and Candy Apples
Ah! Onee-chan will be getting home soon!
I have to prepare breakfast.
I’m finally done.
Looking for
a small puppy
Fireworks
Festival
Now that I think about it, in the past, Asu was the one who really looked forward to the fireworks festival.
But this year...
Okay!
That’s right! The change from yesterday’s grocery shopping.
I’m counting on you. I’ve saved up little by little just for this day.
Onee-chan and I are going to have a lot of fun at the food stands.
Candy apples,
takoyaki,
and rice crackers with sauce.
I’m home!
Welcome home, Onee-chan!
Thank you for your hard work.
Breakfast is ready.
Thanks for the food!
Today's the day of the fireworks festival!
Yeah, it really is!
Hey, after I finish cleaning, may I go out for a little bit?
That’s fine. It is Sunday, after all.
But where are you going?
You’ll find out later.
I’m going now!
Next-door neighbor, your mailbox is full!
It’s really full!
Asu! Be careful, okay?
I know!
Hey, seriously, where are you going?
You’ll find out later.
Ah, Mr. Landlord, good morning.
Well then, me too.
Yes!
Good morning, Asu!
I can’t wait for today’s
fireworks festival!
Kyou
I can’t wait for today’s
fireworks festival!
Go!
Well, if it isn’t Asu-chan!
Hey, it’s Yaoichi’s husband.
Are you going to be selling vegetables at this stand today?
Vegetables wouldn’t sell too well at a festival.
Ah! These are...
Yeah, we’re going to be a candy apple stand today.
Really? A candy apple stand?
My sister and I will come by later to buy one!
Okay! Then I’ll prepare an extra large one just for you.
Thank you very much!
There’s the yakisoba stand, the shooting game stand, and the cotton candy stand.
It’s done!
Ma’am!
I’m home!
Huh? Onee-chan?
T-The money is...
Asu, I’m home!
Sorry I’m so late.
What’s wrong? The lights aren’t even on.
Here, Asu, it’s a present.
A yukata...
Yes!
Where’d you get this?
I bought it at the Hashimoto clothing store.
I have Mom’s hand-me-down yukata, but you don’t have one.
I’ve been wanting to get you one as a present for a while now.
Could it be... you used the money in the piggy bank?
That’s right. Hurry up and try it on!
Eh?
I don’t want it.
Why? I bought this for you, Asu.
Why did you spend the money by yourself?
What do you mean, “why”? I thought you’d like it.
Hey, we can always save money again.
Okay, it’s my fault for spending the money without asking you.
But since the day’s here, wear your new
yukata and let’s go to the fireworks festival.
I’m not going.
Who cares about the fireworks festival?
I’m not going!
Onee-chan, you idiot!
I saved that money for so long,
just so we could spend it together at the fireworks festival.
The takoyaki stand. The rice cracker stand, too...
Everything that I was waiting for!
I really wanted us to eat a big candy apple together!
Asu...
I’m going to return this yukata.
The Yamada family’s
slightly luxurious
dandelion coffee
A bargain sale,
such a glorious sight
Bargain Sale
Rain...
I have to go look for Asu!
Last time...
It’s the same as last time...
Barely made it!
Asu! Asu?
She’s not home yet...
I wonder if she’s okay. Maybe she’s still at school.
If she’s outside, I hope she found shelter from the rain.
I hate thunder!
What if Asu’s also...
Hang in there, Asu.
Your sister is coming to get you.
The lightning—it hit somewhere nearby.
Oh yeah, I think someone told me that lightning is attracted to umbrellas.
Onee-chan!
Onee-chan! Over here! I’m over here!
Come to think of it, Asu wasn’t afraid of the thunder at all.
I’m so pathetic.
That time, I was so scared of the thunder that when I went to get Asu, I almost gave up halfway.
Today, too...
Maybe Asu doesn’t even need a sister like me.
Oh my, Asu-chan.
What’s wrong?
You’re completely soaked!
What if you catch a cold?
Ma’am, this yukata—
Oh, this yukata? You like it, right?
Eh?
It has the same design as your sister’s.
The same?
That's why she wouldn’t accept anything else.
She even went to our warehouse to search for it.
She probably spent the whole day looking.
The whole day?
She probably felt bad because you’ve never had a yukata to wear.
She went to all that trouble just to find a matching yukata for me?
For me...
She was looking forward to wearing matching yukatas and watching the fireworks together.
It’s okay.
It’s just drizzling, so it’ll stop soon.
Rain...
Just like before.
The day I forgot my umbrella.
Ah, more lightning.
Aww, this is inconvenient.
I’ll get home late.
Onee-chan?!
Onee-chan! Over here! I’m right over here!
Onee-chan, you came to pick me up?
But it looks like the rain has stopped.
You didn’t even use your umbrella, did you?
Onee-chan hates thunder, but she braved it to come.
Since you brought them, let’s use them anyway.
Eh? But that’s embarrasing.
All that and yet...
Onee-chan, you idiot!
I... keep causing trouble for my sister.
Kyou is always looking out for you, right?
I told her she was stupid.
Eh?
After all she’s done for me, I called her an idiot.
I...
It’s all right, Asu.
I’m not sure what happened,
but your sister worked hard searching for this yukata.
Why don’t you wear it and show it to her?
O-Onee-chan...
Onee-chan?!
She’s not here.
The fireworks...
Asu!
Beautiful!
Tamaya! Kagiya!
Every year, Asu and I always watch them together.
There’s no point if I’m alone.
Even so, I expected Asu to be here.
Hey, Kyou!
You came just in time.
Your special candy apple is almost done.
Grandpa Yaoichi!
Asu was really looking forward to it.
She said she’d come with her sister.
What? Asu said that?
Yeah.
She came to see what stands there were, saying she wanted to escort you around the festival.
What?
She did?!
This memo...
Asu... she scouted out a plan so she could escort me around.
For me...
Why did you spend the money by yourself?
Who cares about the fireworks festival?
I’m not going!
I’m so stupid.
So stupid!
Here, it’s done! The special candy apple.
Huh? Kyou?
Asu wanted to enjoy the festival with me,
but I didn’t understand her feelings.
Her feelings.
I promised Mother that I’d take good care of Asu.
I promised her.
Excuse me.
Please let me through.
Quickly...
I have to find Onee-chan quickly, before the fireworks are over.
Where are you?
Onee-chan!
Asu?
Asu...
Asu is here!
A-su!
Onee-chan?
Asu!
Onee-chan!
Onee-chan...
Onee-chan, I...
I... I...
Thank you. You wore the yukata.
Onee-chan...
Ah, the fireworks!
Asu, we were able to watch the fireworks again this year.
Yeah.
We got to see them again this year.
Won’t you rest a little?
Asu! Why are you here? Go home!
Onee-chan, I want to work too!
You don’t have to worry about money.
I’ll keep working harder and harder.
It’s all right.
I’ll just get another job.
No...
Onee-chan,
don’t leave me behind.
Don’t disappear like Dad did.
I called you stupid, but even so...
Please, don’t leave me!
Okay.
Onee-chan is right here.
I won’t go anywhere.
It’s all right.
Onee-chan!
Asu, it’s okay. Your sister won’t go anywhere.
Kyou, you don’t have to worry about not working hard enough.
The only thing I was able to leave behind for you two was a small promise, but it’s protecting you dearly.
One day, when you can’t summon the strength...
The sun...
Isn’t it pretty?
Yeah.
My promise somehow protects the bonds between you two.
I will always keep this promise.
Even when everyday talk
He’s returning this month!
The dark lord of riches!
Eh? The landlord hasn’t come yet, has he?
I wonder what happened.
Poor Sisters’ Story:
A Day of the Landlord, Watermelons, and a Visit.
Please watch it!