Dear Onee-sama,
Today, I failed to get the spinach that was on sale.
Am I really qualified to be your younger sister?
Do you hate your little sister who fails repeatedly, after all?
No matter how hard I try, it's never enough to make you notice.
Yamada Kyo,
Yamada Asu, huh...
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
So, we were left behind.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
A Day of Loneliness, Ginko, and Onee-sama
What!? It's already this late?!
Onee-chan, wake up!
Wake up! We're going to be late!
Just three more minutes...
This room is really dark, even in the morning.
All because that complex got built next door.
The weather's great today.
It looks like picking the penthouse was the right choice after all, Onee-sama.
You'd better hurry, Ginko. You're going to be late.
Yes, Onee-sama.
I requested for father to build this complex because the location was much closer to the elementary school.
O-Okay.
You will not be allowed to be late.
Y-yes, Onee-sama.
After that is the big payoff! We'll do some great discount shopping!
Okay.
Though we're only getting some pencils...
Nothing makes me happier than free things.
Weren't they already cheap?
"Economizing". Oh, it sounds so fabulous.
Ah, where's a good ledge to jump off?
Well then, I'll be going ahead by car.
I'll be home late.
Ah... h-have a safe trip.
Onee-sama is busy today, too...
Onee-chan, hurry up!
Okay!
If you don't hurry, we're going to be late!
Ah, it's Ginko-chan!
Good morning!
Good morning.
So you guys moved into the new apartment complex!
It's amazing!
Well, your old house was amazing too, of course.
My father is the owner of this complex.
Because of that, we can live on whatever floor we want, but the penthouse is definitely the best one.
Wow...
I'll invite you over someday.
Onee-chan, your scarf is a little crooked.
Thanks, Asu.
Hey! Listen to me!
Ah, sorry.
Um...
What were you talking about?
Onee-chan, we really need to...
Ah, that's right.
We're going to be late, so let's talk later.
See you later!
Ah, I'm gonna be late!
What the heck is it with those two?
Ah... I barely made it in time.
Could it be that the two of them are always like that?
Stand. Bow.
That's just not the way things are between my sister and me.
Good morning.
Sit down.
Holding hands like that... how embarrassing.
Class representative.
Class representative!
Ah, yes!
What's wrong? Come by the office later to pick up the printouts.
Okay, I got it.
Excuse me.
Ah.
You're also a class representative?
Yeah.
Everyone pushed the job on you, right?
I had to run for it.
When I become a fifth grader, I'm going to run for the student council, too.
Ah, there you are!
I'll definitely be elected president!
Asu, can you please help me with the next part on this?
Oh, sure.
Hey! Listen to me!
Sorry, Ginko.
Please wait just a moment.
It's this part here.
This part here helps to explain this other part here, which leads to this, here.
Oh, I get it now!
Asu-chan, you're amazing!
Let me help you carry that.
What up with her?
She's just letting herself get used.
Right?
You don't seem to be doing anything.
Help pass these out.
Sorry, but we're a little busy right now.
Let's go.
Okay.
Echigoya-san is really annoying, don't you think?{asdfj -> Echigoya
Yeah.
Ginko-chan, sorry about what happened earlier.
Don't follow me!
Didn't I tell you to not follow me?
We walk home the same way, though...
Asu-chan, are you heading home?
Good afternoon.
You know, we made a little bit too much for today, so please take this home with you.
Wow, it looks delicious!
Thank you very much!
You're welcome.
Hey, Asu-chan!
These are today's leftovers. Take them with you!
Ah, okay. Thank you.
Asu-chan! I have some leftovers, too.
Ah. Okay!
Asu-chan, wait! You'd better take this too!
Okay. Thank you very much.
The way you and your sister do your best all by yourselves is really something.
It's rare to see that these days.
Here, this is from our store.
Here. Extras, extras, take 'em.
Oh, you've grown a bit taller, haven't you?
What do you mean it's "really something"?
I'm also... I'm also trying my best just with my older sister.
Why is it...why is it--!
I won't lose to you!
I won't lose to you guys...
Why, why, why?!
Just because she's nicer, has more friends, and she gets along with everyone!
Onee-sama and I are still so much, much, much...!
Ginko.
Yes?
I had that long-range telescope that you were talking about yesterday carried up from the ground floor.
Thank you very much, Onee-sama.
You asked for it so suddenly, I wondered what in the world you wanted to look at with it.
You plan on doing some pretty risky things with it, right?
Ginko.
You going to use this to...
Scout out all the supermarkets in the city for super-great sales, am I right?
That's fabulous, Ginko.
Right, Onee-sama.
If it's for the great cause of economization, I'll even lend you a helicopter if you want.
Onee-sama, I don't think we need to go that far...
Whatever you're doing, it's a great idea.
You should search every single supermarket for deals, even if it takes you the whole day.
Sound good?
S-sure.
I'm sorry, Onee-sama.
That's not why I asked for the telescope.
I have to go now, so I'll leave the rest to you.
What? You're busy today too?
Even though we have the day off.
Yes. I won't be back until late tonight.
Is that so...
Have a good day.
Ah, Miss, I've finished adjusting the settings.
I'll take care of the rest.
Begone.
Understood.
I understand that I really shouldn't be doing this,
I have to do it so I can find out just what is so different between you and us.
We should be perfect.
Even so, even so...
Yamada Asu!
I will definitely not lose to you.
On a cold night, if you eat shichimi, it will warm you up.
To us, the flea market is like an enormous shopping mall.
Thanks for the food!
It's delicious!
The eggs and spinach are delicious!
The day before yesterday, I found the spinach on sale for 40 yen per bag.
And cooked it with some eggs I found yesterday for 58 yen!
Ah! The spinach from the sale that I missed!
Why does this girl open her mouth so wide while eating?
Onee-sama would never do such an improper thing.
She even has grains of rice stuck to her face.
Why do they act so uncivilized?
( ﾟДﾟ)
Hmm?
Onee-chan, your face has some rice stuck to it, you know.
Oh my, you're right.
Ah, Onee-chan, the miso soup also came out really well today.
I've never laughed during a meal before.
Talking with a full mouth is simply reprehensible behavior!
What's wrong, Asu?
Oh, it's nothing.
Today's a holiday, so she's sleeping on the floor in the middle of the day?{休み [やすみ] 1: rest; recess; respite; 2: vacation; holiday; absence; suspension;
I've never seen Onee-sama be that lazy.
Even until she goes to bed, she's always energetic and--
Ginko, good night.
Onee-sama, perhaps you're a little too energetic.
Why does she always seem so happy to take care of her troublesome older sister?
It's rough, isn't it, Yamada Asu.
My sister is never ever troublesome or dependent on me.
Ah, Kyou, Asu, good afternoon.
Good afternoon!
What's this, the two of you are out for a walk?
Yep.
You sure seem to get along well.
You're not anything like my kids. They're always fighting with each other.
They could learn a thing or two from you guys.
No way, you're flattering us, ma'am.
Hmph.
Tada!
Asu, go ahead and pick whichever one you like.
I'll take this one, the dried tuna!
I'll go with the picked plum, then.
Let's eat!
Asu, this pickled plum rice ball is really good!
All they ever think about is food, huh?
All rice balls taste the same no matter who makes them.
There's no reason for me to be jealous of them at all.
Asu-chan, you're early today, aren't you?
Good afternoon!
Thank you for yesterday.
We have the day off today, so I came together with my sister!
Mister, do you have anything that's especially cheap today?
Those two have been together since they woke up.
Miss Ginko, don't you think that spying on people is a little...
I'm through with it.
Watching any more would be wasting my time.
What's wrong, Asu?
Somehow, I can't seem to calm down today...
It kind of feels like someone is watching us.
That's kinda odd, Asu.
Ah, isn't it time for you to deliver the newspaper?
Ah, this is bad! Today's the evening edition, isn't it?
Sorry, can you take these home?
They're a little heavy. See ya!
Take care!
I'm home!
Onee-chan, welcome back.
Dinner is ready.
Ah, thank you.
Miss Ginko, we've completed the dinner preparations.
Just leave it there for now.
As you wish.
Wait.
Yes, is there something you need?
Father hasn't come home yet?
Your father has not yet returned from his trip to Los Angeles.
And your mother...
That's enough.
That's enough. You're dismissed.
Thanks for the food!
Asu! This Salmon Meunière is the best!
The man from the fish market was nice enough to sell us this salmon at a really low price.
And the side dishes are from the owner of the vegetable stand.
"Salmon Meunière" certainly has a rich sound to it.
Though, I didn't put very many croûtons in it.
I'm alright.
I'm fine with being alone.
I was fine, but...
But still, why?
Why am I still drawn to the light in that window?
Huh?
Come over to my house.
Wha-?
I told you before that I'd invite you over!
But it's already so late, and don't you have to ask your family for permission first?
There's nobody there to ask!
Wow! It's so beautiful!
Yeah, isn't it amazing?
The building over there, the tallest one, is ours too.
Along with that one, and that one.
In this area we have a bunch--
No, no, Onee-chan! We're in someone else's house!
You can't fall asleep here!
I'm sorry, it's just that she's always asleep by this time.
Onee-chan!
Ah, wow, she fell asleep.
She's not a very reliable older sister, is she?
That's why you're always working so hard.
It's tough, isn't it.
It's not tough at all.
It's okay. You don't have to fake it.
If it's for Onee-chan, I'll do my very best.
Every day, she works as well as attends school.
She's really the one who has it rough.
Onee-sama...
Because I can't get a real job yet,
for Onee-chan's sake,
I want to make our home the one place in the world where she doesn't have to work hard.
A place where she doesn't have to work hard...
Yes.
Asu... this fried sweet potato is also really delicious.
Well then, we'll head home now.
Okay.
Onee-chan, it's time to go.
Yes... It's delicious.
Geez...
What can I do for my sister?
Excuse me...
Excuse us!
Onee-sama always does her best to meet the expectations of those around her.
And I've never heard her once complain about how tough it is.
Onee-sama is the one who is always alone.
No, I was the one who abandoned her.
Miss Kinko, will it be satisfactory to leave Miss Ginko's new clothes here?
Sure. Just leave them there on the table.
But...
It's fine. I'll take care of them later.
Understood.
Well then, I'll retire for today.
Thank you.
Onee-s--
Onee-sama.
You're not asleep yet?
No.
You'd better hurry to bed, Ginko. You have school tomorrow.
What about you, Onee-sama?
There are still some things that I have to do.
My laundry... You're the one who always folds it for me, aren't you?
Onee-sama!
Onee-sama! Please don't try too hard!
Ginko.
I understand.
Thank you, Ginko.
Dear Onee-sama,
Today, I noticed something for the first time.
I was the one who was wrong.
I was always only thinking about myself.
I didn't even notice how much you had been taking care of me all this time.
I finally understand.
The most precious feelings are those that two people share for each other.
In conclusion, I love you, Onee-sama.
I should be able to handle it.
A place where she doesn't have to work hard.
Please accept this chocolate.
Onee-chan has someone who she likes.
Poor Sisters' Story:
A day of Jealousy, Chocolates, and Valentines.
Please watch it!