For whom shall I sing?
I dislike music.
My heart always manages to find some sadness in the flowing notes.
For whose sake does music exist?
It's that voice again!
Asu!
Is it really some woman's ghost?
D-Don't worry, Onee-chan.
I'm here beside you.
Thank you, Asu.
You're amazing, Asu!
No, I'm not really...
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
A Day of Guitars, Dreams, and a Music Teacher
Good morning, Asu.
Good morning.
Want to compare answers for last night's homework?
Me too, me too.
Okay, sure.
Good morning.
Good morning, sir!
That's it! Thanks a bunch, Asu.
There's nothing you can't do!
Indeed, indeed.
That's not true.
You don't have any weak points, right?
Yeah, she really seems that way, doesn't she?
You're wrong.
It must be nice.
I bet it is. I'm pretty bad at arithmetic, you know.
I'm just human like everyone else.
Fun With Music - Yamada Asu
Music Room
I'm really completely tone-deaf.
Okay. Let's start the music test!
Aida.
Yes ma'am.
Well, then.
~Spring has come and the small stream flows babbling between its banks.~{OH
~The small stream goes whispering between the violets and milk vetches,~
What'll I do?
Ah, I'm terribly nervous. This won't do!
~Wishing them grace, color and beauty, all blossoming on the stream banks.~
Asu, you're the last one on the list, so you'll probably be going next week, right?
Y-yeah.
Are you okay? You're looking a little pale.
~Wishing them grace, color and beauty, all blossoming on the stream banks.~
I'm fine. It's nothing.
I'm looking forward to hearing you sing!
I bet you're really talented!
That's not true! I'm completely tone-deaf!
Okay! Next person.
The people who say that are always the talented ones, right?
You're right. It just seems like Asu is that type of person, too.
No, that's not true at all. I really am tone-deaf.
We can't wait!
~The small stream goes whispering between the violets and milk vetches,~
They're really looking forward to it... What'll I do?
I have a full week from today, so I'll practice every day.
~The small stream in the spring...~
I sound so terrible...
~The small stream goes whispering between the violets and milk vetches,~
What a beautiful voice...
~Wishing them grace, color and beauty, all blossoming on the stream banks.~
Is there someone singing outside?
She's pretty...
...wait, is that a guy?
Good afternoon. You're my neighbor, right?
Y-Yes, I am.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
It's nice to meet you, too.
Um... you're very good at singing, aren't you?
Well, my dream is to become a singer.
You're a singer? That's amazing!
Not at all.
I haven't debuted yet. I'm currently just auditioning over and over again.
Eh?
B-But you sing so wonderfully!
I'm completely tone-deaf.
Hey, listen--
Masao!
It seems that you have a guest.
Masao! Are you in there?
Yeah.
I'll be right back. Wait for me, okay?
"Masao-san". So he is a guy.
I'm coming right now.
It's me! Me!
Yes?
I brought you something.
Thanks.
Eat properly, okay?
Okay.
See you!
Yes?
Masao-san, I made a bento for you.
Thanks.
I'm really looking forward to your next live show!
I'll come again later.
Yes?
Masao-san, um, I hope this isn't a bother, but...
Oh, not at all. Thank you.
Farewell!
Sorry for the wait.
That's really something.
Are they your friends?
Actually, I don't really know any of them.
But they really appreciate my songs.
I also want to hear them.
That's right, one of them said she was looking forward to hearing you play.
Where do you perform?
Last time it was at a live music club, but at the moment I'm taking a break.
I completely ran out of money, so I can't afford any more stage time.
I can hardly afford the rent here.
I've even thought about returning to the countryside,
but with the support of my fans, I can still eat regularly.
So I figured, what the heck.
Usually when I feel like singing, it's already nighttime.
That ghostly voice was him all along.
Oh yeah, I'm Ichinokura Masao. And you?
I'm Yamada Asu.
It's good, you know.
Your singing is.
Well, I'll see you later.
Thanks for the food!
It's good, you know. Your singing is.
If I practice a whole lot, I wonder if I'll ever be able to sing like him.
Asu!
Asu! Asu! It's that voice again!
It's all right, Onee-chan. Listen carefully.
It's singing?
Yes.
That's a really pretty voice.
I wish I had noticed this sooner.
It's a really, really beautiful song.
Ah, good evening. Was I disturbing you?
Not at all, it was a wonderful song.
Good evening. I'm Asu's older sister, Yamada Kyo.
Nice to meet you.
S-Same here.
It seems like it's gotten colder, doesn't it?
Looks like that's all I've got for today.
Well then, goodnight.
Goodnight.
All of the edible items in the plant encyclopedia: memorized.
On a walk, the keeen-eyed can quickly identify edible grasses.
I need get home and practice singing!
I wonder if I'll be able to sing like Ichinokura one day.
I suppose that's not possible.
Oh, it's Ichinokura.
Good afternoon!
Oh, good afternoon, Asu.
Are you on your way home?
Yes, I'm going to go practice sing--
Um, if it's okay with you,
Please teach me... Please teach me how to sing. Please!
We have to take a singing test at school...
It's probably impossible, so it's okay if you say no.
But...
Sure.
You really will? Thank you very much.
Well then, let's get started.
Did you bring anything that can play music?
Um...
A melodica, eh?
Well, I guess it's good enough.
Try making the same sounds as it.
Okay.
Do!
Re!
Mi!
Huh? It won't make the Fa and La sounds.
It's a hand-me-down from my sister, and it's slightly damaged.
Can't you just ask your mom to buy you a new one?
We... Don't have a mom... Or a dad.
It's just the two of you living in that apartment?
Yes.
I'm sorry. I had no idea.
It's all right! I still have my sister.
Um, if there's ever anything I can help with, please ask.
But you're already teaching me how to sing,
S-So...
I'd like to listen to you sing.
Okay, leave it to me. I'll sing for you any time.
To be able to sing in tune and project properly,
every muscle in your body is absolutely essential!
Muscle training menu: sit-ups: 30, push-ups: 20
Okay!
Test
One!
Two!
From then on, with Ichinokura's guidance and help,
Three!
I continued to practice my singing.
Onee-chan practiced too.
Twenty-five! Twenty-six!
Keep going, Asu!
~Spring has come and the small stream flows babbling between its banks.~
~The small stream goes whispering between the violets and milk vetches,~
~Wishing them grace, color and beauty, all blossoming on the stream banks.~
That's it. You did very well.
Okay!
Asu, that was really great!
How can you sing so well?
I guess I just had a really good teacher.
You did it, Asu!
Thanks, Onee-chan.
We should tell Ichinokura, too.
Ah, that's right. Let's go.
Ichinokura-san! I did really well on my test!
Maybe he's not home?
I'm sure he'll be back soon.
It looks like he still isn't back.
A whole week has gone by,
And Ichinokura hasn't come back yet.
I wonder what happened to Ichinokura.
Masao! Are you in there, Masao?
Masao?
Excuse me...
What? Who are you?
Um...
We're his next-door neighbors.
Ichinokura hasn't been home for the whole week.
Have you heard anything from him?
As if!
We told him we'd keep helping him until his next audition, but it seems he deserted us.
Even though he said he would try his best this time!
Then, that means, when he told me he had sold his favorite guitar...
You know he'd never sell it! Masao treasures that guitar more than his own life.
So that's what happened...
Even though he was having his own problems, he still taught me how to sing.
And his music was so wonderful!
And yet...
I'd like to listen to you sing.
Okay, leave it to me. I'll sing for you any time.
Even though he promised me...
He promised that he'd sing for me again...
His song... I can hear it.
His song...
You're right!
Where is it?
That way!
Where?
Masao!
H-Hey.
Geez, Masao.
Where did you go?
Everyone was worried about you.
Masao-san.
Thank goodness.
I was spending the night at my part time job.
It seems I caused you some undue worry.
You idiot.
That's great.
Next time make sure to tell us beforehand!
I'm sorry.
Everyone loves Ichinokura, don't they?
Yeah.
After being turned down at all my auditions,
I started thinking that becoming a musician would be impossible for me.
I decided to give up singing for good.
But...
But, I do want to keep on singing.
That's why I got a part time job, so I could afford to buy back my guitar.
His guitar...
Because I made a promise.
A promise that I would sing for you again.
I sing.
That's what I can do. The only thing I can do.
Music is mysterious.
With the ebb and flow of each note,
I can feel my spirits rising.
That's why I will keep on singing.
That's why I want to stay here forever.
I'll try my best with Onee-chan.
So we will always be able to hear the music.
Asu won a cellphone in a raffle.
Use it carefully!
Onee-chan, why aren't you picking up your phone?
Poor Sisters' Story:
A Day of Emotions, Uneasiness, and Cell Phones.
Please watch it!