We have a winner!
Congratulations!
I-I got it...
That’s right, the third prize!
Let’s see, third prize is... Which one was it?
Ah, here it is!
Tada!
These are the best of their kind, and they come as a set!
Isn’t that great!?
Afterwards, I came to think,
“These are definitely gifts for Asu and me from mother in heaven”.
I’m home.
Welcome home, Onee-chan. Thanks for all your hard work.
Breakfast is ready!
Thanks...
So tired...
Sorry.
That’s fine. Are you okay, Onee-chan?
Yeah.
I’m just spacing out a little.
This won’t do.
I’m going to go wash my face. I’ll be right back.
Onee-chan.
I guess it’s bad manners to be yawning out in public, huh?
No, that’s not what I meant...
Hey, I’m fine, I’m fine.
Well, I’ll see you later. I’m off.
Hey, be careful and don’t forget to check before crossing the street, okay?
Yeah, I’ll be fine!
I guess I’m making Asu worry about me again.
I have to try harder.
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Ever since the paper boy from the next district quit,
I’ve been extra busy filling in for him until they find a replacement.
Oh, hey, Asu!
I forgot to tell her again.
The pickled cucumbers she made for breakfast were really tasty.
The third prize!
Congratulations, Asu-chan!
This is the third prize! It comes as a set!
Premium, prepaid cell phones!
The SIM cards are included.
Now, let’s get that bagged up for you.
C-Can I really have these?
Of course!
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Our father disappeared after accumulating gambling debts.
Thus, we were abandoned.
This is a 40-year-old, one-room, dilapidated apartment with no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
I may be by myself, but I’m not alone.
Hitoribocchi mo hitorikiri janai
ひとりぼっちもひとりきりじゃない
Even if it’s only the two of us, we’re not alone.
Futaribocchi mo futarikiri janai
ふたりぼっちもふたりきりじゃない
Even when seeing my tears about to fall,
Soredemo koboreru namida no mae ni
それでもこぼれる涙の前に
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Egao de shinkokyuu dekiru no kana?
笑顔で深呼吸できるのかな？
Even though we can’t return to our memories,
Omoide ni modore nai kara
想い出に戻れないから
let’s seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kyou wo iki asu wo tsukamou
きょうを生きあすをつかもう
That unreachable jewel
Kakegae no nai kimi no
かけがえのない君の
is there within your heart.
houseki ha kokoro ni aru
宝石は心にある
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
Mukai kaze ni shinkokyuu
向かい風に深呼吸
A Day of Emotions,
Uneasiness, and Cell Phones
Asu!
W-Why do we have these?
There was a raffle in the shopping district today.
These are real, right, Onee-chan?
Onee-chan?
Cell... Phones?
A cell phone means you can carry with you, right?
I’ve always thought that these were mystical devices that only existed in fantasies and stories!
No, you’re exaggerating too much...
Hey, is this a dream?!
I-I don’t think so.
Well then,
I wonder how you’re supposed to use them.
Let’s see. To turn it on, you’re supposed to press...
Is it here?
Where, where?
After that,
um, the prepaid plan gives us 3000 yen worth of minutes to use in three months.
3000 yen worth?
Hey, look at the next part.
“Enter the number, and...”
And after that...
I wonder if they’re ready to use now.
Onee-chan, try calling me.
O-Okay.
It’s ringing!
Hello!
Hello.
Is that how it’s supposed to go?
Did you hang up?
That was a close call!
What was?
We have a limited number of minutes to use on these!
3000 yen worth. We should only use them for important stuff.
Oh, I suppose you’re right.
Onee-chan, are you okay?
Looks like I was doing it again, huh? Yes, I’m fine!
Plus, starting from today, we have these, right?
Tada!
If anything happens, call me right away, okay?
You too, Onee-chan.
Well then, I’m off!
I’m really tired again today.
I forgot to thank her again,
even though the tofu-miso soup was so wonderful.
Oh, that’s right. I need to turn my phone off while I’m in class.
Hey, what are you doing?
Ginko-chan, good morning.
Good morning.
What? You bought a cell phone?!
This? No, I won it in a raffle in the shopping district.
A raffle...
My sister has a phone too, and it’s much fancier and nicer than this one, just so you know!
And when I become a middle schooler,
Onee-sama will buy me one that is just as fancy as hers!
Hey, you should listen when someone is talking to you! What are you doing?
I forgot how you’re supposed to turn it off. What did the manual say again...
You don’t know how to do that?
You hold this button down for a few seconds.
Ginko-chan, you’re amazing! Thanks!
I’m always watching my sister, so I know all about this kind of thing!
If you have anything else that you don’t understand, just ask me for help.
Okay, thanks! See you later.
How lucky... a cell phone.
Asu didn’t call today, eh?
I wonder if I should call her.
Onee-chan hasn’t called yet, eh?
Maybe I should call her.
No, no, that’d be wasteful!
Wait a minute, maybe a time will come when we’ll really need to use these.
If I call now when there’s nothing big to talk about and those minutes get used up...
How come you won’t use it? You should just call her if you want.
Yeah, I guess you’re right.
Maybe this is what they mean by “a poor person’s mentality”.
We’ve already had them for a week, huh?
Yeah.
But we haven’t even used them yet.
If we let the three months just pass by like this...
That’d just be an even bigger waste, right?
Okay! From now on, let’s use them more freely!
S-Sure.
We shouldn’t be wasteful with them, of course—just in case something happens.
Onee-chan, if you put it that way, we’ll just spend another week without using them at all.
I guess you’re right.
The evening papers...
I have to wake up, get out there, and try my best!
Power on!
Yamada-san!
Yes?
Can you give me a hand, please?
Sure!
Onee-chan isn’t answering, even though school’s already over.
I wonder if something could have happened.
Ah, Ginko-chan.
So you finally worked up the nerve to use it, eh?
Yeah, Onee-chan and I decided that we should use them a little more freely.
I wanted to ask her whether she would prefer curry or meat and potato stew for dinner tonight, but...
But both dishes have the same ingredients.
Oh yeah, Ginko-chan, if you want to call us, go right ahead, okay?
Your phone numbers...
Sure, if I feel like it.
Anyway, what could have happened to Onee-chan?
She’s been really tired, so I’m pretty worried.
Our only goal is to make it to
the store-closing-sale on time.
Half Price!
50% Off
On payday, we can have a luxurious
dinner with three side dishes.
You can’t reach her?
Yeah, that’s strange, isn’t it...
Is there a signal?
I don’t have any idea.
It was able to connect to her back at home...
Well then,
let me give my sister a call to check if it works.
Come on, let me give it a try.
Hello?
Onee-sama, it’s Ginko.
Yes, sorry to be calling you so suddenly.
Is everything okay with you at the moment?
Yes, yes. Oh, is that so, Onee-sama.
I heard it was won from a shopping district raffle, yes.
That’s amazing.
I think it was the third prize.
Yes.
If only I could be that carefree on the phone, too.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Yes!
Yes, thank you very much.
Yes.
This isn’t the time for a long conversation!
Ah, um, Ginko-chan.
If you have a long conversation like this on my phone,
um, the 3000 yen limit will get all used up, so...
You’re not even listening.
Um...
Yes, that’s right, Onee-sama. And then, I...
Oh yeah... Onee-chan has been so tired lately,
she probably wouldn’t be up for a long conversation anyway.
Ah, yes.
Ginko-chan, it’s good that you can have a full conversation like this.
Missed Call
Yamada-san, thank you.
Sure!
Hm, what’s this?
Missed Call
Ah, I missed a call.
It’s from Asu!
What? It’s busy?
Okay. That’s the tissue paper from the shopping district?
Okay.
Uh, yes.
You turn the corner at the cigarette store, right?
Hey, um...
Yes, I’ll do just that!
Well then, goodbye for now, Onee-sama.
Thanks.
Missed Call
Onee-chan called, eh?
It’s from Asu!
Hello, Asu?
Ah, Onee-chan—
Asu?
What happened, Asu?
What’s wrong?
It cut out.
Looks like the battery died.
Um...
If you don’t properly charge it, the battery will die really fast, you know.
The number you have dialed is either not currently turned on or is not within range of—
It’s not connecting. What could be wrong?
Maybe something happened.
The number you have dialed is ei—
Ah, Onee-chan—
Something must have happened.
At this time, she’s always in the shopping district.
Excuse me! I’ll be right back!
I wonder what Onee-chan wanted to talk about.
She looked pretty drowsy when she left this morning.
Maybe she started feeling sick?
Say, if you want to recharge the battery, my house has—
Huh? Where did she go?
By this time, she should be at the newspaper office.
Oh, Kyou-chan? Now that you mention it, she doesn’t seem to be here, does she?
She’s not here? Do you mean she never came?
Hey, boss! What should we do with this?
Ah, I’ll be right there.
Um...
Onee-chan... If she did really get sick, she could be anywhere.
You know, now that I think about it, Kyou-chan was here just a while a—
And now she’s gone.
Oh, Asu-chan? No, I haven’t seen her yet today.
Is that so?
Now that you mention it, she’s usually here by now, isn’t she?
Here you go! Thank you!
Eh?
This is strange. Asu wouldn’t purposefully hang up on me like that.
No way!
Was she kidnapped?!
Onee-chan, where could you be?
Maybe she wasn’t feeling well so she went back home.
—not within range of reception or—
Asu!
Onee-chan!
The number you have—
Come on!
Onee-chan, Onee-chan, where are you?!
Onee-chan!
Come on! Now that we have cell phones, how come they won’t work at a time like this?!
Onee-chan!!!
Asu!
Asu!!
Onee-chan!
Asu!
Thank goodness! You didn’t collapse after all.
The same goes for you. You weren’t kidnapped.
Thank goodness.
Onee-chan.
Really? The reason I couldn’t connect was because the battery died?
Yeah, there was a lot that happened.
Same here. It was just because of bad timing that I wasn’t there to answer your call.
In the end, it was all by chance, but it sure wore us out.
For sure.
Oh, on that topic, what was it that you called about the first time?
I just wanted to ask if you would prefer curry or meat and potato stew for dinner tonight.
Is that really all?
Sorry.
Meat and potato stew sounds great.
Okay.
Who could that be?
Hello.
Oh, she’s right here.
Ginko-chan?
It seems that you managed to find your sister, right?
Yeah.
That’s great. I was worried.
Um, well...
I’m sorry for using up your phone’s battery!
I hope I didn’t end up causing too much trouble.
No, you didn’t.
Anyway, I’m also going to get my own cell phone!
I see. That’s great.
Well then, see you tomorrow.
See you.
Ginko-chan said she’s getting a cell phone too.
That’s good.
Yeah.
O-Onee-chan... the evening newspaper route!
You even still have the bicycle they lent you.
Anyway, try your best!
I’ll make delicious stew for you!
Onee-chan, are you all right?
I’m fine, I’m fine.
Oh, I forgot to tell Asu how good the fried eggs were this morning.
Hello. Onee-chan?
Ah, Asu, you know...
What is it? Is something the matter?
Are you feeling—
The fried eggs you made for breakfast were excellent!
That’s it.
That’s all I wanted to tell you, Asu.
Thanks. Not just for this morning’s breakfast but for every single one, Asu.
Don’t push yourself too much, Onee-chan.
It didn’t happen immediately,
but I eventually decided that these phones were a present from our mom in heaven.
I got the feeling that I was being told, “It’s okay to relax a bit”,
from both mom and Asu.
Alright! Giving it another shot?
Hah, you two. This has to be the 50th time in a row that you’ve tried.
You’re obviously after something.
What is it you want so badly?
The third prize: the cell phones.
Onee-sama, we’re already out of raffle tickets.
If that’s the case, go buy some things to earn more.
Yes.
Mr. Attendant, prepare for our return.
Onee-sama, thank you for allowing me to have a cell phone.
But...
Just buying it the normal way would definitely be cheaper.
Even when everyday talk
Taai nai oshaberi ga
他愛ないお喋りが
gets interrupted,
Fui ni togire ta toki mo
ふいに途切れたときも
all I need is you by my side,
Koushite soba ni iru dakede
こうして側にいるだけで
so I feel safe and sound.
Anshin dekiru
安心できる
That kind face of yours
O teko wo “fuwari” naderu
おてこを“ふわり”撫でる
is just like a gentle wind.
Soyokaze mitai ne
そよ風みたいね
We tightly hold each other’s hands,
Gyutto gyutto te to te wo tsunai dara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと手と手を繋いだら
and run up that hilly path together.
Sakamichi wo kake agarou
坂道をかけ上がろう
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Ashita mo zettai tanoshii ne
明日もぜったい楽しいね
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Naran de yukou
並んでゆこう
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Gyutto gyutto kaze wo tsukamae tara
ぎゅっとぎゅっと微風を捕まえたら
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Ryuote hiroge todoke tai
両手ひろげ届けたい
We tightly hold each other’s hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Gyutto gyutto ashita mo asatte mo
ぎゅっとぎゅっと明日も明後日も
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
Naran de yukou iishoni yuko o
並んでゆこう一緒に行こう
Binbou   Shimai Monogatari
Asu, do you remember anything about mom?
I remember we made a promise.
Poor Sisters’ Story:
A Day of Colds, Promises, and Mother
Please watch it!