It's done!
Since I had nothing prepared, I just let the chocolate melt and then freeze it back into a new shape.
I wonder if she will be happy...
Valentine chocolate!
I really want to give this out already, to my favorite...
Yamada Kyo.
Yes!
Hooray!
Even though you sleep the entire day...
Onee-chan!
Mother went to heaven the year she gave birth to Asu.
Father left a huge debt after gambling and is now missing,
leaving only the two of us.
The place we live in is
a beaten up 40 year old apartment with one room and no bath.
This is our home.
But, when spring comes...
Omoitei modorenai kara
Even though we can't return to our memories,
Kyou wo ikii asuotsukamo
let's seize today and search for tomorrow.
Hitorimo ochimo hitorikiri janai
I may be by myself, but I'm not alone.
Futarimo ochimo futarikimi janai
Even if it's only the two of us, we're not alone.
Soredemokoboreru namida no mae ni
Even when seeing my tears about to fall,
Egao nashi ugokyuu dekiru noka nai
can I still smile and take a deep breath?
Omoitei modorenai kara
Even though we can't return to our memories
Kyou wo ikii asuotsukamo
let's seize today and search for tomorrow.
Kagega eno naikimi no owoseki wa kokoro ni aru
That unreachable jewel is there within your heart.
Mukai kaze ni shingokyuu
Face the oncoming wind and take a deep breath.
A Day of Jealousy, Chocolate, and Valentine's Day
It's all right! Just leave it up to Onee-chan!
From school to work, that's what Onee-chan says.
It's really tough, actually.
But she always keeps up a smile.
This is the first time I've ever made chocolate for Onee-chan.
How should I give this to her...
"Thank you for everything!" sounds a little strange...
3:30, eh...
Oh yeah, I should go pick up Onee-chan.
She hasn't come out yet... Onee-chan.
Maybe she's left school already...
Please accept this!
Um... about that...
Please accept this chocolate!
And then, please read the letter inside. I beg you!
Good bye.
Onee-chan... already has someone she likes.
What should I do with this chocolate...
I'm back!
I'm hungry... what's for dinner tonight?
Even though it's Onee-chan... it's normal that she has someone she likes, right?
Asu?
Asu!
What's wrong? Spacing out like that...
No... nothing at all.
Really?
All right, Onee-chan will help you with those.
It's fine, I can do it myself.
Nah, here, let me.
I said it's fine!
Asu...
So-sorry. It's fine, I can do this myself.
Onee-chan should go get some rest.
If Asu says so... then okay...
I don't think I can give it to her anymore... my chocolate...
Did you guys see the soccer game from yesterday?
I did, I did.
The opponent wasn't that strong.
It's the person that Onee-chan likes.
I couldn't help it, but the other team was a bit cheap.
I wonder what kind of a person he is...
As her younger sister, I have to find out.
I'm back!
Asu isn't back yet...
Ahahaha... welcome back.
There're club activities tomorrow, right?
Yes, that's correct.
Let's try hard tomorrow.
Good bye.
See you tomorrow.
He has quite a number of friends.
Good bye.
He helped that grandma carry her suitcase.
Ah, he even helped her up the stairs.
He... might be a good person.
But, but, but! This isn't enough, I can't hand over my sister just yet.
Ah, he let his seat to a pregnant woman.
Ah, he gave the wallet he found to the police.
Ah, he got back the balloon that the kid lost.
Ah, he's giving directions to a lost foreigner.
No, no! That's still not enough!
I still can't accept him with only these reasons.
I must find out his true self.
Ah, he even recycles.
How is this possible... he's too perfect!
(The neighboring town has meat to eat, so the distance doesn't seem too far.)
(We got off two stations early and finally bought meat with the money we saved this month.)
He's a good person.
No wonder Onee-chan likes him.
Hmmm... just what am I doing....
Eh? Onee-chan?
I'm... I'm back.
Welcome back.
What's this?
Ah...
I found it!
You were acting a little strange since yesterday... I wanted to ask what was wrong...
This chocolate must be the reason, right?
Hey hey, who are you giving this to?
It couldn't have been... me?
Onee-chan doesn't even want my chocolate, right?
Huh?
Yesterday you gave chocolate to a guy.
Ah.
You saw that, Asu?
One day... one day... Onee-chan will go to that person's side...
Leaving me all alone...
You don't even want my chocolate, right?!
Asu!
Onee-chan...
Onee-chan won't accept my chocolate.
Maybe... I can't ever give chocolates to Onee-chan...
Even if she accepts it,
she'll just say that she's glad to get it.
But... she won't be truly happy, right?
Because... Onee-chan already has someone she likes.
I'm just an annoying child...
Asu...
I think I really should cheer Onee-chan on...
What is this feeling...
Ah, it's that person.
Who's he waiting for...
What if it's... Onee-chan?
Why... did he go off with another girl...
Why...
Asu!
Onee-chan!
Thank goodness... so you were here.
Tha-thank you.
Um... Onee-chan.
I was just here... and then... um...
Meat buns!
Oh yeah, meat buns!
I saw an advertisement that said there will be meat buns for sale at 10 yen each.
10 yen!? Where was this ad?
Oh no... I set the price too low.
If we don't hurry, they'll get sold out.
Hey, where are the advertisements?
Um... that... uh...
Over there!
I understand. It's over there.
Asu, let's go!
Where is it advertised, Asu...?
Uh... that... where was it again...?
It probably sold out.
Eh!? No way...
I wanted to eat them with Asu...
If she knew that the one she likes has a girlfriend already,
Onee-chan will probably be very sad.
No. He's the type of person who accepted the chocolate but went off with someone else.
Those types of people are better off dumped by Onee-chan.
Ah! Uh... Onee-chan, that...
Ah!
I found it! The 10 yen meat buns!
Eh?
Ah! It's really 10 yen.
You're amazing, Onee-chan. You really found it.
What are you talking about? You're the one that's amazing, because you found it first.
Ah! Anyway, let's go in first.
If they can pass us while we're entering this store than that'd be great.
Welcome.
Um... are these meat buns really 10 yen a piece?
Yes. Right now we're having a special promotion.
Would you like to buy one?
Yes, please give me two.
But... if she saw a picture of him holding another girl's hand...
Onee-chan will probably not like him anymore.
If that happens... I...
For Onee-chan's sake... What I can do...
Onee-chan!
What's wrong, Asu?
Onee-chan, since it's rare that we've come here,
let's buy two more, so it's two for each of us.
That's great, the two of you got together fine.
Because I didn't say anything afterwards, I was worried about how it turned out.
I see, I see.
I'm happy too.
That's great.
If something happens later, tell me.
Yes, thank you.
I gave that chocolate as a favor for one of my classmates.
I-I see...
I mistook it for something else... how embarrassing.
Sorry, tricking you like that.
But, Asu.
If you become worried later about something like this again,
just remember that Onee-chan will not leave you alone.
I definitely won't.
Yes.
But, Asu was worried about me, so I was happy.
Eh? What's wrong?
I don't care anymore.
Ha, I'm sorry, you angry?
I don't care.
Ah, don't leave me alone.
Thinking about someone else...
Bringing that person a warm coat to wear...
Then finding cheap meat buns to eat together...
Once I think that Onee-chan will one day do such things for someone else,
I feel a little sad.
I think when that time comes, Onee-chan will definitely not leave me alone.
So, even if I answered, "Yes", will that be fine?
If... that time really comes...
Anyway, Asu.
Who are you giving this chocolate to anyway?
To my favorite person!
Eh? Who's that?
Wait up! Asu!
Who is your favorite person?
That's why... the choice I make... is the one that will bring happiness to favorite Onee-chan.
Ta ainaiosha be iga
Even when everyday talk
Fuinito gi re ta tokimo
gets interrupted,
Ko oshite sobani iru dakede
all I need is you by my side,
Anshin tekiru
so I feel safe and sound.
Obekowo ruwa ni na de ru
That kind face of yours
Soyokaze ni tai ne
is just like a gentle wind.
Gyuto gyuto te to te wo tsunaitara
We tightly hold each other's hands,
Sakamichi wo kage a ga ra wo
and run up that hilly path together.
Ashita wa zettai tanoshiine
Tomorrow will definitely be another happy day.
Nara n de yuko o
Let us walk shoulder to shoulder.
Gyuto gyuto kaze wo tsu kama e tara
I tightly hold on to that flowing wind,
Ryuote hirogeto doketai
in order to spread my arms out and give it to you.
Gyuto gyuto ashita no asa atemo
We tightly hold each other's hands tomorrow and the day after that.
Nara n de yuko iisho ni yuko o
Shoulder to shoulder, let us walk ahead together.
I hear a ghost... a ghost's voice, Asu.
It's... It's all right Onee-chan, I will be by your side.
Binbou Shimai Monogatari
A Day of Guitars, Dreams and the Music Teacher.
Please watch it!