Binchou
tan
Your kindness is like
sashidashita kokoro wo iro tsuketa
差し出した心を色付けた
the morning dew you can see when you first wake up.
sou kimi no sono yasashisatte
そう君のその優しさって
It almost looks like it's being blended into the light
hayaoki shita asa no shizuku mitai
早起きした朝の雫みたい
Binchou-tan
It gives color to my heart when I show you.
hikari e to suikomaresou nanda
光へと吸い込まれそうなんだ
Chiku-tan
What I realize at those moments...
fu to shita toki ni kizuku mono
ふとしたときに気づくもの
Kunugi-tan
is that I'm really looking for where I belong;
ibasho wo sagashiteta
居場所を探してた
Ren-tan
I want to stay there.
watashi koko ni itai
私ここにいたい
Aloe
Our days are being filled with love as they're formed
aito yuu hibi ga umareteku
愛という日々が生まれてく
Time stands still.
ima kono toki ga tsuzuiteku
今このときが続いてく
The important place is here, so I'm going.
taisetsu na basho ga koko ni aru dakara yuku yo
大切な場所がここにあるだから行くよ
Mr. Ubamega
Tama Frog
Pukashu
Gramps
Madake
Grandpa Suda
Granny
Ume
Chisanoki
Sensei
Don't just stare at walls.
takai kabe wo miagete nai de
高い壁を見上げてないで
Taking another path can be fun too.
yorimichi datte tanoshii
寄り道だって楽しい
I hope the days I can think like this continue,
sou omoeru hibi de irareru you ni
そう思える日々でいられるように
so I can keep walking.
watashi wa aruite yukeru
私は歩いて行ける
It's morning.
This is Kunugi-tan's mansion.
Kunugi-tan is waking up.
She is always cheerful when she wakes up.
It looks like today will be a very special day for her.
This is Chiku-tan's house.
Today I'm bursting with liveliness!
At Ren-tan's home, Momi Temple...
She's off to perform the daily rituals.
And at Aloe's house...
Aloe, wake up!
You're going to be late!
Now that we're done with swimming lessons, I don't want to go to school.
Hurry up and get changed.
Saji's House
Saji looks like he's still a bit sleepy.
I'm off.
Attached Stag Beetle-bin
Today's the day I'll be able to meet Binchou-tan at school.
I'm off!
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
I hope I can sell a lot of medicine today.
I'll work hard!
This is the school Kunugi-tan attends.
Chishanoki-sensei was pleased with Binchou-tan's work,
so now she works at this school every week.
Does anyone need some medicine?
It's really effective medicine!
I have several different kinds!
This treats stomach aches. Would you like some?
Are you sure it works? It smells kind of strange.
It works. It tastes slightly bitter, but it works really well.
I hate bitter stuff!
I'll pass, my son is pretty stubborn.
Let's go buy some sweet tasting medicine.
I have medicine that works really well!
Creams to soothe bug bites and cough medicine too!
This spot isn't very good for business.
I'll show you somewhere much better.
Eh?
Kunugi
Binchou-tan
This is my name.
Ku-nu-gi.
Below is your name, Binchou-tan.
Wow...
Now, try copying it.
Bi
Bi...
n... chou...
That's it!
You're really good!
Next is a greeting.
Ko-n-ni-chi-wa
Would you like some really effective medicine?
I'll take this.
Thank you very much!
I need some disinfectant.
Thanks!
Thanks for your patronage.
nichiwa
Ah, a drone beetle.
It flew away.
I'm afraid of bugs.
Oh yeah!
Some pretty flowers are blooming on the other side of the annex.
Let's go look at them.
Sure.
Come again!
Thanks! I was able to sell everything thanks to you!
Err...
Ren-tan.
Ren-tan, I'd like to do something to thank you.
In that case, you can buy me some Taraya dango.
A stag beetle...
Hey...
Look! I can see them!
Those flowers.
They're cute flowers.
Aren't they wonderful?
Yeah.
Taraya
What are these?!
They're delicious!
Taraya dango are my favorite food.
I hope you like them too.
They're really, really tasty!
Taraya
I have to tell Binchou-tan about them!
She probably already knows...
The sun sure is bright...
All the water I splashed on myself at school has evaporated.
Today was really fun! Thank you.
Let's try drawing next week.
Yeah!
Well then, I'll be off.
Well then...
She liked Taraya's dango.
I must let more people know about them.
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
Grandpa, I was able to sell all the medicine thanks to her!
And the dango we ate after that were really delicious!
I'll take you with me next time, Chiku-rin!
Aloe!
How long are you going to be awake?
You'll have a hard time waking up.
Fun Pools
Hurry up and get to bed.
Okay!
Fun Pools
I want to go to the island south of here,
so I can swim all year round.
If I can't, I'd be happy with a more durable pool.
That's the normal wish from the normal me.
A mail bird?
Thank you ever so much.
Binchou-tan
Kunugi-tan, hello.
The end.
I...
...love...
...living!
Next Time
The Sweet Potato Season-bin
I don't have many acorns left...
I'm off.
The Sweet Potato Season-bin
Good morning.
There we go.
Binchou-tan has opened up a shop for today.
She isn't offering a wide variety,
but it's still popular with the townsfolk.
She takes money as payment,
but accepts other forms as well.
Thank you very much.
What?!
Binchou-tan!
Where'd you get those?
I exchanged some mushrooms for these sweet potatoes.
But I won't be able to eat all of these by myself.
Now that you mention it, I see what you mean.
Here.
I can have one?
Yeah.
Thank you!
You still have so many left, though.
I wonder what I should do.
I know!
I've got it!
Eh?
That's for me?
Yeah.
Please take it.
We wanted to share them with you.
That is a sweet potato, Miss.
This is... a sweet potato?
Yes.
They taste delicious when they are baked.
A baked potato, right?
Thank you, Binchou-tan.
Bye Bye!
It's a good thing you were able to give one to Kunugi-tan.
What is a baked potato?
Eh?
A "yakiimo" (焼き芋) is a baked sweet potato.
Surely it's just like a yakiimo?
It sounds really classy.
Wow, that sounds great.
I know, how about we make some yakiimo too?
Yakiimo?
Yeah, some baked potatoes!
A baked... potato?
Let's go to Ren-tan's place!
Saji, let's go!
Ouch...
It's a sweet potato.
Momi
Temple
Crow
Mountain
We came to sweep your yard!
Crow
Mountain
Oh my.
There are two cute helpers today.
Excellent, excellent!
I was just thinking I needed some help raking up the fallen leaves.
I'll leave things to you.
Sure thing!
Leave it to us!
Wait, was today the day they were scheduled to come?
Gather all the leaves into one spot, Binchou-tan.
Okay!
It's noisy.
Mukugyo
ma
mi
mu
me
Ah, Ren-tan!
Perfect timing!
Say, I have a small favor to ask of you.
Here, I brought some.
Thank you.
Hold it like this...
And fold it here, and here...
And wrap it up like so.
The preparations are done!
All we have left to do is put this
inside of the pile of the burning leaves.
I see.
So this is why you swept up all those leaves.
Yakiimo certainly taste like Autumn, wouldn't you agree?
We're not cooking yakiimo, we're cooking baked potatoes!
Huh?
A ba...ked...?
Oh!
What's that?
I'd like this sweet potato for dinner, cooked medium-well.
Certainly, Miss.
Mommy, can you bake this?
Why do you have that sweet potato?
I waited all day to eat it.
All day?
Yes.
It's just an ordinary sweet potato.
It should be done soon.
Really?
Hey, wait!
It's hot, so you can't touch it with your bare hands!
Tada!
The Magic Hand!
Woah!
If you use this, you won't burn yourself.
Here, Binchou-tan. Put your hands out.
Here.
Oh, sorry!
I didn't think that far ahead.
It's sweet and delicious!
Although it's not on par with dumplings, it's not too bad.
It's nice and toasty.
It tastes like grandma's.
It's so delicious!
Let's put these in too.
If you do that...
Everyone, get away!
Hurry!
It's ready, Miss.
Thank you for waiting.
Enjoy your dinner, Miss.
Thank you for the food!
It's sweet and tender!
It tastes completely different from a regular potato.
I wonder if the others are eating theirs as well.
There.
It's done baking.
The warm skin is yummy.
It's the taste of Autumn.
It sure brings back memories.
That sure was fun when the roasted chestnuts were shooting out of the fire!
Yeah!
And the sweet potato was delicious!
I'd like to eat them again with everyone.
Me too.
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
Well, Binchou-tan, I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
Gramps, Chiku-rin! I'm home!
Sorry it's so late.
I brought back some yakiimo.
Hey, Saji! You need to go back to your own home!
I'm back.
Ku-nu-gi-ta-n... ko-n-ni-chi-wa...
Was your... sweet potato... tasty?
Mine was... tasty.
The... end.
ohayou hamigaki bin bin bin
おはようはみがきビンビンビン
Good Morning. Brushing her teeth. Bin bin bin.
bin bin genki ni bin bin bin
ビンビン元気にビンビンビン
Bin bin. Being energetic. Bin bin bin.
kashinoki sarasara konnichiwa
かしの木さらさらこんにちは
An oak tree gently waving hello.
taiyou san san ii tenki
太陽さんさんいい天気
The sun is shining, it's a beautiful day.
kyou mo machi made dekakemasu
今日も街まで出かけます
She's going to town again today.
shigoto ga hai reba icchau yo
仕事が入ればいっちゃうよ
She goes whenever there's work to do.
bonyari gao shita binchoutan
ぼんやり顔したびんちょうたん
She has an absent look on her face.
mita me ni niawazu
achichi no chicchi
見た目に似合わずあちちのちっち
Seeing it, you'd say she's unfit.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san
no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Next Time
First Snow, First Sled, First Flight-bin