Binchou
tan
Your kindness is like
sashidashita kokoro wo iro tsuketa
差し出した心を色付けた
the morning dew you can see when you first wake up.
sou kimi no sono yasashisatte
そう君のその優しさって
It almost looks like it's being blended into the light
hayaoki shita asa no shizuku mitai
早起きした朝の雫みたい
Binchou-tan
It gives color to my heart when I show you.
hikari e to suikomaresou nanda
光へと吸い込まれそうなんだ
Chiku-tan
What I realize at those moments...
fu to shita toki ni kizuku mono
ふとしたときに気づくもの
Kunugi-tan
is that I'm really looking for where I belong;
ibasho wo sagashiteta
居場所を探してた
Ren-tan
I want to stay there.
watashi koko ni itai
私ここにいたい
Aloe
Our days are being filled with love as they're formed
aito yuu hibi ga umareteku
愛という日々が生まれてく
Time stands still.
ima kono toki ga tsuzuiteku
今このときが続いてく
The important place is here, so I'm going.
taisetsu na basho ga koko ni aru dakara yuku yo
大切な場所がここにあるだから行くよ
Mr. Ubamega
Tama Frog
Pukashu
Gramps
Madake
Grandpa Suda
Granny
Ume
Chisanoki
Sensei
Don't just stare at walls.
takai kabe wo miagete nai de
高い壁を見上げてないで
Taking another path can be fun too.
yorimichi datte tanoshii
寄り道だって楽しい
I hope the days I can think like this continue,
sou omoeru hibi de irareru you ni
そう思える日々でいられるように
so I can keep walking.
watashi wa aruite yukeru
私は歩いて行ける
Heart of the Mountains
House 1-1
To:  Binchou-tan
From:  Ubamega
Bin's Birthday-bin
Happy
Birthday!!!
May 7
from,
Ubamega
Thank you, Ubamega-san.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday to me.
I'll be on my way.
Entrance to the Countryside
Services may be canceled due to weather
Fare - 1 Acorn
Pidgeon's Bus Union (Fly)
Please make your
way to the
foot mark, crouch, and wait
Timetable
Morning
Afternoon
Evening
Night
Clear Weather
Rainy Weather
Bus Stop
I'm off!
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
All right, take care.
Will do!
I wanna go too!
Hey, Chiku-rin!
It's such a beautiful day.
Today I'll do my best!
Have a safe journey, miss.
I wonder if there's any way I could get to town faster.
I could take bigger steps.
But I need longer legs for that.
I need to come up with a good idea.
Thank you very much.
What's this?
I'm sorry.
It's fine, it's fine.
You're bleeding.
Hold on.
I'm sure I...
Found it!
Disinfectant and ointment.
My family runs a pharmacy.
This might sting a little.
Bear with it a moment.
That should do it.
It turned out better than I expected.
I'm Chiku-tan.
I'm Binchou-tan.
I'm also on my way to find work.
Let's look together.
Sure.
Let's go.
I've got it.
Binchou-tan, give me a hand!
Ready?
Yay!
It worked really well!
Today's going perfectly.
Here.
Oh, this is on the west side of town.
Mine is on the east side.
I guess it's goodbye for now.
Yeah.
See you later.
Bye-bye.
All right, does everyone understand so far?
Anyone who doesn't understand, please raise your hand.
Okay. Then here's the next problem.
Medicine Prescriptions
This                  way
Found it! Disinfectant and ointment.
It turned out better than I expected.
Hey!
Binchou-tan! What happened?
Ah! You fell down again!
I've got it!
Wait right here.
I have a great idea.
Sorry for the wait.
Put it on top of this.
See? The rice doesn't go through.
We're really close to my house.
You should stop by.
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
Grandpa, we have a guest!
Oh, do come in.
Welcome!
Miss.
Your dinner is ready.
Happy birthday, Binchou-tan!
See, it was meant to be a suprise.
Come, sit down.
Happy
Birthday!!!
May 7
Happy
Birthday!!!
May 7
Happy
Birthday!!!
May 7
Happy
Birthday!!!
May 7
I found this near the job bulletin board.
May seventh is today.
This is merry. Very merry.
Hey! Don't do that!
Thank you for the meal.
This is my invention.
A bamboo lamp!
An invention!
That girl who flew through the sky...
I wonder who she is.
It's bright!
Now, we're all set!
Happy birthday, Binchou-tan!
How joyous.
Happy birthday!
Ah, thank you.
Next Time
Rainy Sunday-bin
It's raining again today.
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
Chiku, it's time to wake up.
Okay.
Good morning, Miss.
As it's Sunday, please have a leisurely breakfast.
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
Yay!
It's finally done!
My newest invention!
The joke is that the name Chiku gave to her new invention is an alternate reading of "takeuma" (竹馬), meaning "stilts."
"Chikuuma"!
An invention!
Chiku,
they're called "stilts."
They've been around for a while.
You can even buy them in town.
But I'm the one who thought of it!
But I'm the one who came up with it!
I wanted to get to town faster somehow!
I thought so hard about my new invention!
I invented it first!
I'm the one who thought of it!
I'm the one who came up with it!
I've had enough!
It doesn't matter!
Chikuuma, departing!
I know! I know!
I've got it!
Services may be canceled during rainy weather
Hey!
Binchou-tan! Today's Sunday, so the town hall's closed.
What do you think of this?
My newest invention lets you walk around in the rain without getting wet.
Chikuuma, "Shitoshito-kun"!
You can even use it to walk through puddles!
Miss, here is your green tea.
Um...
May I have another sweet?
Honestly, Miss!
What's this?
Is this your hideout?
Y-Yeah.
I want one!
What do you want to play?
I don't know.
Then I'll think of something.
In Shiritori (尻取り), you take the last syllable of a word the other person
says and continue the game by saying a new word starting with that syllable.
I know, let's play shiritori.
I know how to play that.
Grandma taught me.
Because the syllable "n" (ん) isn't at the beginning of any words in Japanese, whoever says a word with it at the end loses.
Remember, you'll lose if you say a word that ends with "n."
I'll go first.
Invention
Hatsumei.
Mr. Dog
Inu-san.
Don't add "san."
Just say inu.
Stuffed toy
Nuigurumi.
Pukashuu.
You didn't use the last syllable.
Mi...
Nattou (納豆) is fermented soybeans which are renowned for their smelliness. Mito (水戸) is the town from which nattou originated.
Mito Nattou.
U...
Cow
Ushi
Shi...
Sheets
Shiitsu.
Fishing rod
Tsurizao.
Rice
Okome.
Mentaiko (明太子) is a food made from pollock roe marinated in chili.
Mentaiko.
Kome hikari is the premium rice of Japan, distinguished by its aroma, sweet flavor and sticky texture. However, it's usually referred to as "koshihikari."
Kome hikari.
Squirrel
Risu.
Sumi (すみ) can mean either charcoal (炭) or ink (墨).
Sumi
Mitanattou!
I used that one earlier.
What's that?!
My friend.
But he only comes out on rainy days.
Binchou-tan, that's amazing!
Let's walk through the outer yard.
That's a cute flower.
That's a purple dead-nettle.
I wonder what kinds of flowers bloom out there?
This is as far as we go.
Let's head back.
What's for snack today?
It finally stopped.
So, what should we do now?
Umm...
Well then, come to my house and we'll finish our game of shiritori, okay?
Okay.
I found this neat shortcut when I was coming here.
We'll need to go through a bamboo grove though.
Man, I don't want to carry this back!
I'll leave it here.
Miss,
if I may, I would like to show you something.
Right now?
Yes, right away.
Wow, amazing!
Look, look!
This is it, Miss.
Please look around.
That's so pretty.
And there's another one too.
ohayou hamigaki bin bin bin
おはようはみがきビンビンビン
Good Morning. Brushing her teeth. Bin bin bin.
bin bin genki ni bin bin bin
ビンビン元気にビンビンビン
Bin bin. Being energetic. Bin bin bin.
kashinoki sarasara konnichiwa
かしの木さらさらこんにちは
An oak tree gently waving hello.
taiyou san san ii tenki
太陽さんさんいい天気
The sun is shining, it's a beautiful day.
kyou mo machi made dekakemasu
今日も街まで出かけます
She's going to town again today.
shigoto ga hai reba icchau yo
仕事が入ればいっちゃうよ
She goes whenever there's work to do.
bonyari gao shita binchoutan
ぼんやり顔したびんちょうたん
She has an absent look on her face.
mita me ni niawazu
achichi no chicchi
見た目に似合わずあちちのちっち
Seeing it, you'd say she's unfit.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san
no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Next Time
Kimono Memories-bin