Binchou
tan
Your kindness is like
sashidashita kokoro wo iro tsuketa
差し出した心を色付けた
the morning dew you can see when you first wake up.
sou kimi no sono yasashisatte
そう君のその優しさって
It almost looks like it's being blended into the light
hayaoki shita asa no shizuku mitai
早起きした朝の雫みたい
Binchou-tan
It gives color to my heart when I show you.
hikari e to suikomaresou nanda
光へと吸い込まれそうなんだ
Chiku-tan
What I realize at those moments...
fu to shita toki ni kizuku mono
ふとしたときに気づくもの
Kunugi-tan
is that I'm really looking for where I belong;
ibasho wo sagashiteta
居場所を探してた
Ren-tan
I want to stay there.
watashi koko ni itai
私ここにいたい
Aloe
Our days are being filled with love as they're formed
aito yuu hibi ga umareteku
愛という日々が生まれてく
Time stands still.
ima kono toki ga tsuzuiteku
今このときが続いてく
The important place is here, so I'm going.
taisetsu na basho ga koko ni aru dakara yuku yo
大切な場所がここにあるだから行くよ
Mr. Ubamega
Tama Frog
Pukashu
Gramps
Madake
Grandpa Suda
Granny
Ume
Chisanoki
Sensei
Don't just stare at walls.
takai kabe wo miagete nai de
高い壁を見上げてないで
Taking another path can be fun too.
yorimichi datte tanoshii
寄り道だって楽しい
I hope the days I can think like this continue,
sou omoeru hibi de irareru you ni
そう思える日々でいられるように
so I can keep walking.
watashi wa aruite yukeru
私は歩いて行ける
Saji's House
It sure has gotten cold.
Sa
Binchou-tan, do you have enough supplies for winter?
I have some rice.
Eh?!
Will you be alright with just that?
If it snows a lot, you may not be able to get into town.
I guess.
But I don't have any money.
Saji's House
I know!
Let's go and do some bartering like we did the other day!
Saji's House
I'm sure that there are still some things growing, like nuts or mushrooms.
I'll help out as well, so let's do our best and gather as much as we can!
Saji's House
Yeah!
Between their jobs, the two of them gathered a variety of things in the mountains.
First Snow, First Sled, First Flight-bin
Pay a low price or barter
A few weeks later,
the small market they opened up in the town turned out to be a huge success.
Going splish-splash, drifting on the waves, if I think about it, I've come a long way.
I've seen this scenery before.
I've finally returned home!
It looks today's episode of The Adventures of Pukashuu will be the last.
I'm going to try my luck at the lottery over on the main shopping street.
Wait here, okay?
Noshiba
Electronics
Open
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
Let me see...
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
Three nights, four days
Hot Springs Vacation
First Prize
First prize is a...
...bicycle!
I want it!
Lottery
Oh, it's Chiku-tan.
But I'm never lucky when it comes to the lottery.
Oh, it's you, Ren-tan!
Are you shopping?
Yes.
Are you going to try your luck with the lottery?
I got a couple of lottery tickets, but I have no faith in winning.
I have rotten luck.
If you hold this for me, I'll draw in your place.
Eh?!
Consolation Prize
Hold this.
We have a winner!
First prize!
You won a bicycle!
You did it!
That was amazing!
Everyone, I'm back!
I'm finally home!
The Adventures of Pukashuu
Season One - The End
Binchou-tan!
Sponsors
Kouraku Pharmaceuticals
Minabe-dou
We won!
Huh?
I can see lots of things, lots of different things...
Thank you!
Please take these!
These aren't half bad.
Good work, Saji.
Anyway, bye-bye, Binchou-tan
I've thought up a new invention with this bike!
I can't wait to try it!
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho...
Bye-bye!
Thanks to Chiku-tan's help, it looks like Binchou-tan is all set for the winter this year.
Warm and fuzzy.
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
He
re's
to a
good
ar!!
ye
Ubamega
An end of the year present?
Binchou-tan!
We got a lot of supplies yesterday, so let's play in the snow today!
The open field looks like fun!
Ah, it's Ren-tan!
Thanks for your help yesterday!
Fast, so fast!
I'll play too.
An invention?
These are "skis."
They were lying around the house.
I've never used them before, but I brought them along anyway.
It looks pretty easy!
Let me try too.
Stop me! Stop me!
Thank you, Saji.
Father!
It's so cold...
I hate running errands on days like these.
I don't like winter.
I want to take a swim in a big hot spring.
When I said that I wanted to meet up with you, a friend of mine lent this to me.
I'm afraid of heights, but since he went to all the trouble, I flew over anyway.
Do you want to ride in it too?
I would love to!
You aren't scared?
If I'm with you, I'll be fine!
I see.
Have a safe trip, Master.
And you too, Miss. Take care.
I'm off, Jii!
I'm flying...
It's like a dream.
This must be the scenery Binchou-tan saw.
I would like to go towards the mountains.
Balloon!
Kunugi-tan!
Amazing...
She's flying through the sky!
That sure looks fun. I want to fly too.
I'm interested in doing that.
Eh? In flying?
Temporary increase in available flights
Fly whenever you want
Pidgeon's Bus Union (Fly)
Here.
Make sure you give it to Mr. Birdy before landing.
I'm flying...
I'm really flying!
Interesting.
Mr. Birdy, that way please.
Hey! Kunugi-tan!
Binchou-tan!
Chiku-tan!
Ren-tan!
Hey!
I'm so cold!
I'm dizzy!
If only it would hurry up and be summer again!
By giving them the chance to fly, Binchou-tan felt like she was able to repay Chiku-tan and Ren-tan a little for all they had done.
Next Time
A Letter to the Sky-bin
It's cold...
It's really cold, Granny.
Granny, wait for me!
I'm really tired already.
Do your best on your own.
Wait up, Granny!
Granny?
Granny!
Where are...
It's lodged in.
It looks painful.
It won't budge.
Granny...
There we go!
Pound!
Making mochi!
Makin' mochi!
Ren, what are you doing?
Training for tonight.
Oh, you're going to help me ring the bell?
I'm grateful for your help.
Finally, our New Year's preparations are done.
Toshikoshi-soba (年越しそば) are buckwheat noodles which are traditionally eaten in Japan on New Year's Eve.
Now then, how about we order some toshikoshi-soba?
Yeah, we have to have toshikoshi-soba on New Year's eve.
You need to get a good night's sleep tonight.
If you don't get enough sleep, you won't be able to properly ask God for a wish.
Yes, Father.
Sudajii, please take good care of Kunugi.
It's my pleasure, master.
Good night, Father.
Kunugi
Binchou-tan
Are you awake?
How are you feeling?
Your fever is down, right?
I'm so glad that Grampa's medicine worked.
It's a special New Year's dish with Taraya dumplings inside.
If you eat it, you'll get much better.
M-Miss...
I made that mochi yesterday.
Now, go ahead and try eating some.
Okay.
Is it tasty?
Yeah.
It's very tasty.
A New Year's package has arrived for Bin-sama.
It's so cold.
It doesn't feel like a New Year unless I visit the shrine on the first day of the New Year.
I have to draw a fortune, too.
Fortunes
Medium
Luck
"Something to the northwest of here holds the ability to change your luck."
Ski! Ski!
I want to try it too!
Hey, Chiku-rin!
It's dangerous if you run!
We're not out here to play.
We're just bringing Kunugi-tan back home.
Binchou-tan?
Binchou-tan!
Miss!
What's wrong?
What are you doing, Binchou-tan?
I'm writing a letter to my Granny.
To your Grandmother?
Yeah.
A New Year's greeting?
What's going on?
I want to write something too.
Here.
Thank you.
What are you guys doing?
Let me join in!
Me too!
Cold...
Ren-tan
Mokugyo
dumplings
Grandma,
I made a lot of friends.
Bin
My name is Kunugi
I'm Chiku-tan!
Chiku-rin is here too!
You tried your best, so you were able to make friends, Binchou.
Binchou-tan
Mountain Home
Happy New Year!