Binchou
tan
Your kindness is like
sashidashita kokoro wo iro tsuketa
差し出した心を色付けた
the morning dew you can see when you first wake up.
sou kimi no sono yasashisatte
そう君のその優しさって
It almost looks like it's being blended into the light
hayaoki shita asa no shizuku mitai
早起きした朝の雫みたい
Binchou-tan
It gives color to my heart when I show you.
hikari e to suikomaresou nanda
光へと吸い込まれそうなんだ
Chiku-tan
What I realize at those moments...
fu to shita toki ni kizuku mono
ふとしたときに気づくもの
Kunugi-tan
is that I'm really looking for where I belong;
ibasho wo sagashiteta
居場所を探してた
Ren-tan
I want to stay there.
watashi koko ni itai
私ここにいたい
Aloe
Our days are being filled with love as they're formed
aito yuu hibi ga umareteku
愛という日々が生まれてく
Time stands still.
ima kono toki ga tsuzuiteku
今このときが続いてく
The important place is here, so I'm going.
taisetsu na basho ga koko ni aru dakara yuku yo
大切な場所がここにあるだから行くよ
Mr. Ubamega
Tama Frog
Pukashu
Gramps
Madake
Grandpa Suda
Granny
Ume
Chisanoki
Sensei
Don't just stare at walls.
takai kabe wo miagete nai de
高い壁を見上げてないで
Taking another path can be fun too.
yorimichi datte tanoshii
寄り道だって楽しい
I hope the days I can think like this continue,
sou omoeru hibi de irareru you ni
そう思える日々でいられるように
so I can keep walking.
watashi wa aruite yukeru
私は歩いて行ける
The festival is today.
Ramune and Candy Apples-bin
It's complete!
It's an invention that allows you to live wherever you want!
Invention!
You pull it around using the pole on top. It's a house that can go anywhere.
If I set up close to town, it'll be so much easier to get to work.
Now then, let's move it already.
Already!
It broke!
Breast stroke.
Back stroke!
My pool!
I don't want anything for my birthday, so please buy me a wading pool.
We just bought one the other day.
What happened to it?
There's a hole in it.
The air...
It's leaking out.
Our family is....
I feel sorry for you, but no more.
Here, take a look at this.
Mandarins
This makes four.
Mokugyo Fortune Telling
We'll pick spots according the color of the beads we draw.
Please play fairly.
Okay, first up.
Hachibee
All right, next person.
Oh, Ren's here.
Welcome, welcome.
Are you going to try too?
I am.
It's the gold bead!
I want this spot.
The best spot!
Damn it!
Central Town Pool
One children's ticket please.
My money!
What was that, Jii?
Today is the summer festival.
Those are the fireworks I told you about.
Apparently the Lantern Festival dance is also taking place tonight.
The Lantern Festival dance?
I know what that is.
It's a dance party, isn't it?
That's right.
Water...
Someone's collapsed!
You need some water?
Here, water.
Thank you!
You're welcome!
Huh? I... still... feel... dizzy...
Oh, no! That was grandpa's sake!
Good Fortune
Summer
Festival
Good Fortune
Very Accurate
Very
Accurate
Mokugyo
Fortune
All I have left to do is put the mokugyo up here.
Mokugyo
Fortune
Telling
Mokugyo
They're getting restless again...
Hey!
Binchou-tan!
Meet me when you're done with work.
Let's walk around together.
A "Torii" (鳥居) is a traditional Japanese gateway to a Shinto shrine.
I'll wait for you by the Torii at the top of the steps, okay?
Okay.
Well then, see you later!
A summer festival...
I wonder if she'll be there too?
Wow!
Miss!
Miss.
It is time for your lunch.
All right.
I wanna try! I wanna try! I wanna try!
Go for it!
Yay!
You need to start off relaxed.
Then you snap the stick back just before it hits.
Gotcha.
You're not bad!
This is fun!
I'm starting to see it...
To find what you're looking for, you will need to go south...
ohayou hamigaki bin bin bin
おはようはみがきビンビンビン
Good Morning. Brushing her teeth. Bin bin bin.
There are so many stalls!
Festivals are awesome!
bin bin genki ni bin bin bin
ビンビン元気にビンビンビン
Bin bin. Being energetic. Bin bin bin.
Taiyaki (鯛焼) are fish shaped pastry filled with bean paste.
Taiyaki!
kashinoki sarasara konnichiwa
かしの木さらさらこんにちは
An oak tree gently waving hello.
Wow, there are so many people!
taiyou san san ii tenki
太陽さんさんいい天気
The sun is shining, it's a beautiful day.
It's just how I imagined.
So... dizzy...
kyou mo machi made dekakemasu
今日も街まで出かけます
She's going to town again today.
shigoto ga hai reba icchau yo
仕事が入ればいっちゃうよ
She goes whenever there's work to do.
bonyari gao shita binchoutan
ぼんやり顔したびんちょうたん
She has an absent look on her face.
mita me ni niawazu achichi no chicchi
見た目に似合わずあちちのちっち
Seeing it, you'd say she's unfit.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
I'm exhausted.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
But still, this festival's the best!
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
The best!
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Binchou-tan sure is late.
You can go after you take the trash out.
Thank you for working hard this late.
Thank you very much.
You are an average person.
Tomorrow will be another average day.
For better or for worse, everything will be average.
Eh?!
I want to go home.
Just a little longer.
Binchou-tan will be here soon, okay?
Okay.
Ah! She's here!
Here?
Binchou-tan!
You're late!
The festival's almost over!
Here, I bought you a candy apple.
Thank you.
Chiku-rin waited too.
Now, let's go!
It's really noisy now.
It's hurting my head.
Follow me.
I'll give you something nice.
Eh?
Pretty...
Excuse me.
Huh?
I won too many prizes. Since I have more than I can handle, will you help me out?
Yay! We'll help, we'll help!
Miss.
Huh?
Jii.
I bought this for you.
What is it?
It is a drink called Ramune.
So this is... Ramune?
Will you drink it?
It's pretty!
Here.
I suddenly felt a chill!
A blue flame went down there.
Eh?!
No way!
Seriously.
Get it out!
Okay!
Next Time
Musunde Hiraite-bin
Thank you for the meal.
Note: Musunde Hiraite is a Japanese nursery rhyme that involves various hand actions.
Musunde Hiraite-bin
Have a safe trip, Miss.
Hello.
Um... Well,
I'm sorry about earlier.
With this, you can get some new clothes.
I don't need it.
Take care, Miss.
Okay, do you understand everything so far?
Children's Reception Desk
Hello, this is the director of the Town Hall Children's Reception Desk.
Handmade Korokke!!
Delicious
Korokke
A "korokke"(コロッケ) is the Japanese variant of a croquette. It's a deep fried
food, and is quite often served with tankatsu sauce and shredded cabbage.
Was there something you liked, little lady?
Where's your mother?
Let's do "Musunde Hiraite"!
Here we go!
Close and open!
Musunde hiraite
Clap your hands and keep them closed together.
Te wo utte musunde
Open them again, clap them together, and hold them up in the air.
Mata hiraite te wo utte sono te wo ueni
Okay, everyone, good job!
I'm back!
Welcome home.
Thank you for the food.
Madake Pharmacy
Medicine Prescriptions
How cute!
Is it yours?
No, it followed me home from town.
Woof, woof!
He doesn't have a collar, so is he a stray?
But Grandpa told me that stray dogs are taken to the animal shelter.
Eh?!
He seems used to people, he was probably abandoned.
Eh?
H-Hey!
Maybe we can keep him.
He seems to like my portable house.
If we do it together, we'll be able to take good care of him.
For sure.
Yeah.
I want to look after this little guy.
So it's decided!
Well then, let's make him a collar right away!
It's done!
That's cute!
Yeah, it really suits him!
Oh yeah, we have to give him a name!
A name?
He likes korokke, so how about "Koro"?
That sounds a bit too common. He's an abandoned dog, so how about...
Saji?
Yeah, let's go with Saji!
The meaning behind this comes from the Japanese idiom, "saji wo nageru" (匙を投げる). It literally translates to "throw a spoon"...
Since he's a dog that was given up on.
Saji, Saji!
...but can mean "to give up on something." "Saji" (spoon) is the first word of the idiom, so this is where he gets the name from.
Saji.
Let's put Saji's house halfway between your house and mine.
Saji's House
Children's
Reception Desk
From 8 am
To 1 pm
Children's Reception Desk
She was quite pleased with the work you did, so she wants you to come back.
It seems like she likes you a lot!
I'm really happy for you.
So, will you do it?
Yes!
I've been waiting for you.
I think you already heard, but if it's alright with you,
coming here and working on a weekly basis would really help me out.
How about it?
Yes.
I'll try my very hardest.
Please look after me.
Now then, here's the next question.
Hanako-san and Tarou-kun were really close friends, but...
Even though it's September, it's still really hot.
I want to go to the pool.
Saji!
Where are you going?!
What the?
This...
...makes me dizzy.
Saji!
Don't run so fast!
Oh?
He won't stop!
What should I do?!
Saji!!!
Finally, he stopped.
I was taking him for a walk, and he suddenly sped off.
I think he must have picked up your scent.
It's a dog!
It looks friendly!
Who does he belong to?
There's a dog!
Let's go see him!
That collar's cute.
He's called Saji.
Sa-ji.
I thought his name up!
He was abandoned, so I named him Saji!
Miss!
Do you like dogs?
He sure is cute.
I've never touched a dog before, so I'm really happy!
Saji's pleased too.
Today I found out that girl's name, thanks to Saji.
I made friends with them.
Chiku-tan, Saji, and Binchou-tan.
She laughed too.
Today was really fun.
Saji...
ohayou hamigaki bin bin bin
おはようはみがきビンビンビン
Good Morning. Brushing her teeth. Bin bin bin.
bin bin genki ni bin bin bin
ビンビン元気にビンビンビン
Bin bin. Being energetic. Bin bin bin.
kashinoki sarasara konnichiwa
かしの木さらさらこんにちは
An oak tree gently waving hello.
taiyou san san ii tenki
太陽さんさんいい天気
The sun is shining, it's a beautiful day.
kyou mo machi made dekakemasu
今日も街まで出かけます
She's going to town again today.
shigoto ga hai reba icchau yo
仕事が入ればいっちゃうよ
She goes whenever there's work to do.
bonyari gao shita binchoutan
ぼんやり顔したびんちょうたん
She has an absent look on her face.
mita me ni niawazu
achichi no chicchi
見た目に似合わずあちちのちっち
Seeing it, you'd say she's unfit.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san
no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Next Time
Attached Stag Beetle-bin