Binchou
tan
Your kindness is like
sashidashita kokoro wo iro tsuketa
差し出した心を色付けた
the morning dew you can see when you first wake up.
sou kimi no sono yasashisatte
そう君のその優しさって
It almost looks like it's being blended into the light
hayaoki shita asa no shizuku mitai
早起きした朝の雫みたい
Binchou-tan
It gives color to my heart when I show you.
hikari e to suikomaresou nanda
光へと吸い込まれそうなんだ
Chiku-tan
What I realize at those moments...
fu to shita toki ni kizuku mono
ふとしたときに気づくもの
Kunugi-tan
is that I'm really looking for where I belong;
ibasho wo sagashiteta
居場所を探してた
Ren-tan
I want to stay there.
watashi koko ni itai
私ここにいたい
Aloe
Our days are being filled with love as they're formed
aito yuu hibi ga umareteku
愛という日々が生まれてく
Time stands still.
ima kono toki ga tsuzuiteku
今このときが続いてく
The important place is here, so I'm going.
taisetsu na basho ga koko ni aru dakara yuku yo
大切な場所がここにあるだから行くよ
Mr. Ubamega
Tama Frog
Pukashu
Gramps
Madake
Grandpa Suda
Granny
Ume
Chisanoki
Sensei
Don't just stare at walls.
takai kabe wo miagete nai de
高い壁を見上げてないで
Taking another path can be fun too.
yorimichi datte tanoshii
寄り道だって楽しい
I hope the days I can think like this continue,
sou omoeru hibi de irareru you ni
そう思える日々でいられるように
so I can keep walking.
watashi wa aruite yukeru
私は歩いて行ける
Spring Awakening-bin
A little girl lives in an old house deep in the mountains.
Her name is Binchou-tan.
And so another day begins for Binchou-tan.
Um, this is for the ride.
Thank you very much.
Please help me out again sometime.
Binchou-tan freezes up when she's suprised.
It's not that she's scared of snakes.
She was just a little bit taken aback.
Nice and warm.
Binchou-tan doesn't have any parents.
She lives all alone in the mountains.
However, she isn't lonely.
Although life in the mountains isn't very convenient,
the riches of nature more than make up for it.
Amongst all of that, Binchou-tan lives every single day to its fullest.
Thank you for the food.
Dinner was delicious today, too.
Next Time
Getting a Job-bin
A little girl lives in an old house deep in the mountains.
Her name is Binchou-tan.
And so another day begins for Binchou-tan.
There's no more rice.
Binchou-tan works in the town.
She has to leave for work today, too.
I'm leaving.
Getting a Job-bin
Entrance to the Countryside
Services may be canceled due to weather
Fare - 1 Acorn
Pidgeon's Bus Union (Fly)
Please make your
way to the
foot mark, crouch, and wait
Timetable
Morning
Afternoon
Evening
Night
Clear Weather
Rainy Weather
Bus Stop
Here is the bus stop.
Now then, what kind of bus will come?
Please wait here
Binchou-tan waits patiently.
Here it comes.
Thank you very much.
This is the town where Binchou-tan works.
First, she has to find a job.
Binchou-tan tries again and again.
Deodorizing shoes?
I can't do something like that.
I can't do this one either.
Today she managed to find a lot of jobs.
Binchou-tan will do anything she can.
She does her best no matter what.
And there are some things only she can do.
For example,
imagine this.
And...
this as well.
Thanks for the help.
The rice came out perfectly.
I hope you'll help me out again.
You did an excellent job,
so I gave you some extra rice.
Shrine of the Myna Toys
Super Popular!
Print Panties
six hundred Yen
There isn't enough...
Special Bargain Sale
70% Off
White.
Pink.
Striped.
There's one!
Print panties!
Method of payment?
Cash, please.
Here.
The exact change? Thank you.
Oh, hold up.
Shrine of the Myna Toys
Thanks again.
Have a safe trip home.
Binchou-tan's favorite is Pukashuu.
However, she also loves Tama Frog, so she's very happy.
And just like that, Binchou-tan's workday ends.
Thank you for the food.
ohayou hamigaki bin bin bin
おはようはみがきビンビンビン
Good Morning. Brushing her teeth. Bin bin bin.
bin bin genki ni bin bin bin
ビンビン元気にビンビンビン
Bin bin. Being energetic. Bin bin bin.
kashinoki sarasara konnichiwa
かしの木さらさらこんにちは
An oak tree gently waving hello.
taiyou san san ii tenki
太陽さんさんいい天気
The sun is shining, it's a beautiful day.
kyou mo machi made dekakemasu
今日も街まで出かけます
She's going to town again today.
shigoto ga hai reba icchau yo
仕事が入ればいっちゃうよ
She goes whenever there's work to do.
bonyari gao shita binchoutan
ぼんやり顔したびんちょうたん
She has an absent look on her face.
mita me ni niawazu
achichi no chicchi
見た目に似合わずあちちのちっち
Seeing it, you'd say she's unfit.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san
no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Next Time
Bin's Birthday-bin