Binchou
tan
Your kindness is like
sashidashita kokoro wo iro tsuketa
差し出した心を色付けた
the morning dew you can see when you first wake up.
sou kimi no sono yasashisatte
そう君のその優しさって
It almost looks like it's being blended into the light
hayaoki shita asa no shizuku mitai
早起きした朝の雫みたい
Binchou-tan
It gives color to my heart when I show you.
hikari e to suikomaresou nanda
光へと吸い込まれそうなんだ
Chiku-tan
What I realize at those moments...
fu to shita toki ni kizuku mono
ふとしたときに気づくもの
Kunugi-tan
is that I'm really looking for where I belong;
ibasho wo sagashiteta
居場所を探してた
Ren-tan
I want to stay there.
watashi koko ni itai
私ここにいたい
Aloe
Our days are being filled with love as they're formed
aito yuu hibi ga umareteku
愛という日々が生まれてく
Time stands still.
ima kono toki ga tsuzuiteku
今このときが続いてく
The important place is here, so I'm going.
taisetsu na basho ga koko ni aru dakara yuku yo
大切な場所がここにあるだから行くよ
Mr. Ubamega
Tama Frog
Pukashu
Gramps
Madake
Grandpa Suda
Granny
Ume
Chisanoki
Sensei
Don't just stare at walls.
takai kabe wo miagete nai de
高い壁を見上げてないで
Taking another path can be fun too.
yorimichi datte tanoshii
寄り道だって楽しい
I hope the days I can think like this continue,
sou omoeru hibi de irareru you ni
そう思える日々でいられるように
so I can keep walking.
watashi wa aruite yukeru
私は歩いて行ける
I'm off.
Kimono Memories-bin
I'm gonna be late! I have to hurry!
Did you get your lunch?
I don't have time!
Even if you're hungry, eating grass from the roadside won't do.
Here are some rice balls. Take them along.
Take care on your way.
I'm off!
Off!
Hold up. You're staying here.
Knock stones together!
I guess it can't be helped.
Be careful when knocking the stones together.
Look here, Chiku-rin, the pain's coming out.
Pain
Pain, pain, fly away!
Today, Binchou-tan has come to find some work.
Got it.
Got it!
My stretchy "magic hand" worked really well! What a great success!
It's a great success!
I'm helping out with school lunches. What did you get?
Children
Reception Desk
From 8 am
To 1 pm
A job at the bakery.
Okay, your registrations have been processed.
The job at the bakery starts tomorrow. The job at the school is the day after tomorrow, all right?
The day after tomorrow?!
What do I do?! The day after tomorrow is the big tool fair!
And on top of that, I saved all that pocket money!
Hey, what should I do?
Well, let me give you some advice for the time being.
I'll give you my riceballs, so will you please trade jobs with me?
The baker uses an oven with open flames,
so make sure you listen to what he says and be careful.
The owner may appear scary, but you'll be fine.
Okay.
Thanks!
And that's it. Do you understand?
It's a prestigious school, so make sure you dress a bit more nicely than usual, alright?
And that's how the job arrangement was settled.
Bye-bye.
Make sure you dress a bit more nicely than usual. It's a prestigious school, after all.
It's brand new...
Never mind...
Today is her day to work, but because it's raining, Binchou-tan has to walk to town.
Oh, dear. Look at you.
Don't tell me you're the one helping out today.
Yes, nice to meet you.
First, dry your clothes, wash your hands, and put this on.
You can't work with such dirty clothes on.
Weren't you told to come wearing nice, clean clothes?
I washed them thoroughly.
They're my treasured clothes.
Now then, I need you to distribute lunches to each classroom.
Is that all right?
All right.
When passing by a classroom, you must be
extremely quiet and move along slowly.
You can walk a little faster.
Wow! It's huge!
A classroom!
Mr. Rabbit bought five 10-yen apples and three 20-yen tangerines. He received 40 yen back—
Class is in session. What was that sound?
Teacher, that... that... To pick up the eraser... I hit my head, and...
Because of the rain,
the tool fair is canceled
What?! And I collected all that pocket money, too!
She's crying.
Please finish eating your lunch before the students do.
Um, since I didn't bring any lunch, if there is any more work to do, I'll do it.
Oh, is that so? In that case, we'll clean the windows and hallway floor.
Thanks for the food.
We're going to meet in the gym.
I'll go on ahead!
Wait up!
Not again, so many leftovers. Let's clean this up.
The hallway Binchou-tan cleaned is sparkling.
Here is your wage for the day.
Thank you very much.
Here she comes, Miss.
Hello.
Um... Well, the carriage that accidentally splashed mud on you this morning was mine.
I'm sorry about that.
With this, you can get some new clothes...
I don't need it.
Why didn't Binchou-tan accept the money?
Which color do you like, Binchou?
Pink! Pink!
Mine, Mine!
That's right. Since there's a lot, let's make two, okay?
Yay! Two! Two!
Is it done?
Not yet.
Hold on, almost done.
Look, it's done. It's really cute!
It's my very own!
Grandma!
These clothes cannot be bought with money.
They're my treasured clothes.
Next Time
Nighttime Buddhist Services-bin
On this summer morning, perhaps we'll encounter someone new.
Crow
Mountain
Momi
Temple
Noshiba
Electronics
The Adventures of Pukashuu
Going splish-splash, floating on the waves,
where will Pukashuu go today?
Huh? I heard a cry somewhere.
Mr. Jellyfish is here!
How about this one? It's a brand new, twenty-inch color television.
Don't cry. I'm sure you'll be able to see your friends again.
Really?
I'll make it cheap!
Let's go search for them together!
How many channels do you get on it?
Huh? What's that?!
It's connected to the Jugoto broadcasting office, so they're all on there.
Yikes! It's Mr. Shark!
Run for it! It's dang—
Here.
Cooking in Three Minutes for Wives.
Daily Living Information Corner!
Today's theme is how to make delicious rice.
Aoki Bread and Cakes
Fluffy
Chou a la Creme
Aoki Bread and Cakes
Fluffy
Chou a la Creme
Binchou-tan can't help but wonder what will happen to Pukashuu next.
Today is going to be noisy.
This girl's name is Ren-tan. She lives in a temple.
She is very perceptive when it comes to spiritual matters.
She seems to be sensing something right now.
I  wonder what that was?
Did I win?
You lose
That's too bad. Here's a small chocolate for trying.
How'd it go?
I got a small one.
You
lose
My ice cream was a loser too.
I haven't won a single time this summer.
One winning chocolate, please.
Ah, welcome Ren-tan.
I'll give one to each of you.
A winner!
Yeah, this is the winning chocolate!
It sure is big!
Big!
Thank you!
Oh, what a cute helper we have today.
Well done, well done!
Now then, let's wipe this Buddha statue clean.
Even stone Buddhas have souls!
If you put your heart into cleaning the Buddha, it will truly rejoice.
He's always watching over everyone from afar.
So always be considerate and be a good girl.
Taraya
You did very well today.
Take these home with you.
Dango are ball shaped treats made of rice flour that come in different flavors. They're soft, sticky, chewy, and often served with green tea.
My grandchild loves dango.
Ah, Ren-tan, leaving already? Thanks for coming.
Taraya's dango are Ren-tan's favorite dish.
She spends most of her pocket money on them.
Ksitigarbha, otherwise known as Jizou-sama (地蔵様) in japanese, is a Mahayana Buddhist Bodhisattva...
There's a statue of Ksitigarbha out here?
Ah! Taraya's dango.
...who is known to watch over children, travellers, and the underworld.
Ren, are you cleaning?
That's just what I expect from my grandchild. How kind of you.
I can rest easy when you're doing these things.
The mokugyo (木魚) is a fish-shaped wooden temple drum used in Buddhist services.
Ren-tan loves mokugyo very much.
She performs Buddhist services which even the adults don't know about.
I-It's not here!
Dear, do you know where my mokugyo went?
Ah, it's right there.
Oh, it really is. I guess I'm a little tired.
Noshiba
Electronics
Wait up!
Going splish-splash, floating on the waves, where will Pukashuu go today?
The Adventures of Pukashuu is having an evening rebroadcast
Mr. Jellyfish is here!
Don't cry. I'm sure you'll be able to see your friends again.
It's just begun.
Really?
This time, it looks like Binchou-tan will be able to watch it all the way to the end.
Let's go search for them together!
Huh? What's that?!
Yikes! It's Mr. Shark!
Run for it! It's dangerous!
Sorry, Mr. Shark. You're not going to be able to eat us now.
Anyhow, let's fly like this over to everyone else!
Ah! Everyone's over there!
I'm glad we found them so quickly!
We don't need to worry now.
Thank you, Pukashuu!
Mr. Jellyfish was able to return to his friends.
Congratulations, congratulations!
Good for you, Mr. Jellyfish.
Make sure you dry yourself thoroughly or you'll catch a cold.
I'm going to go take a walk for a bit.
Dear, go ahead and take your bath.
Ren-tan's real Buddhist services take place at night.
See? Something's gathering.
That delivery took so long. It's getting late, and it's completely dark out.
Huh? I hear something.
Is anyone there?
Noo! Noo! Noo!
A ghost with black hair!
It was wet!
Oh, it's dark!
Medicine Prescriptions
Madake Pharmacy
Ah, sorry about that. I ran out of oil.
She's crying.
Ah, I need to go to the bathroom.
Hey, hey? Chiku-rin, do you need to go to the bathroom?
A lil' bit.
I'll take you along.
Big...
Grab this rope. If something happens, pull it.
You there?
Yeah, I'm here.
Chiku-rin, you still there?
There are lots of us here!
You're there? Thank goodness.
"Lots of us"?
Chiku-tan is afraid of ghosts. She got to eat the big chocolate today, but saw some frightening things, too.
ohayou hamigaki bin bin bin
おはようはみがきビンビンビン
Good Morning. Brushing her teeth. Bin bin bin.
bin bin genki ni bin bin bin
ビンビン元気にビンビンビン
Bin bin. Being energetic. Bin bin bin.
kashinoki sarasara konnichiwa
かしの木さらさらこんにちは
An oak tree gently waving hello.
taiyou san san ii tenki
太陽さんさんいい天気
The sun is shining, it's a beautiful day.
kyou mo machi made dekakemasu
今日も街まで出かけます
She's going to town again today.
shigoto ga hai reba icchau yo
仕事が入ればいっちゃうよ
She goes whenever there's work to do.
bonyari gao shita binchoutan
ぼんやり顔したびんちょうたん
She has an absent look on her face.
mita me ni niawazu
achichi no chicchi
見た目に似合わずあちちのちっち
Seeing it, you'd say she's unfit.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san
no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over here.
ganbari ya san no Binchoutan
がんばり屋さんのびんちょうたん
Such a hard worker, Binchou-tan.
Binchoutan Binchoutan
びんちょうたんびんちょうたん
Binchou-tan, Binchou-tan.
a sore
あそれ
Over there.
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
dareka ga matteru yonde iru!
だれかが待ってる呼んでいる！
Someone is waiting and calling for her!
Next time
Ramune and Candy Apples-bin